【XTM 字幕组】 http://cnX264.com 荣誉出品
翻译：banana  se7en_up 校对：逃逃 jesseding
[加勒比海   1970年]
[The Caribbean, 1970]
[银行大劫案]
[The Bank Job]
[根据真实事件改编]
[Based on a true story]
[伦敦东区   1971年]
[East London, 1971]
又一辆"特里.莱泽牌九成新车"完工了
Another "Terry Leather Low Mileage" done.
你很开心真好 明天的婚礼都准备好了吗?
Good you're glad, but have you all sorted out for your wedding tomorrow?
没错 当然了 特里
Yeah, of course, Terry.
新西装 双排扣的 9英寸侧襟
New suit, two buttons, 9 inch pump flaps.
不错啊 英格丽肯定会喜欢的
Nice. Ingrid will like that.
明天结婚了哈 英格丽?
So, you're getting married tomorrow, Ingrid?
但愿如此
I hope so.
别在这浪费时间了
Go on, get off now.
快去打扮打扮 让自己更漂亮点儿
Go make yoursef more beautiful than you already are.
如果可能的话
If that's possible.
特里
Terry.
答应我今晚别让艾迪喝太多酒 好吗?
Promise you won't get Eddie too legless tonight, will you?
在他的单身聚会上
At his stag do? (bachelor party)
我们就是去酒吧 喝喝酒 唱唱歌
We're just going round the pub, couple of pints and a sing song.
哦 该死...
Oh, fuck...
妈的 你们想怎么干嘛? 啊?
Fuck it, what are you trying to do to me, eh?
我会还给基索钱的
I've got Jessul's money.
问题是这钱靠这些车来赚
The Problem is, it's tied up in these cars,
你们这些混蛋却把它们都砸了
and you wankers want to trash the lot of 'em.
基索先生不在乎你怎么赚钱
Mr. Jessul doesn't care about your inventory.
基索先生只在乎你是不是还钱
Mr. Jessul wants to know that he's getting paid.
尽快 我发誓 猪大头
Any day, I swear, Perky.
你叫我什么?
What did you call me?
我叫你"猪大头" 猪大头!
I called you Perky, Perky!
大家都这么叫你 叫他猪二头
Everyone calls you Perky, and him Pinkey.
- 猪大头和猪二头? - 对
- Pinkey and Perky? - Yeah.
动画片里猪的名字
They're fucking cartoon pigs on the telly,
什么 大家在背后这么叫我们?
what, people call us that behind our backs?
好吧 我以后不当面叫了 行吧?
Well, I'm not gonna say it to your face, aren't I?
你刚才已经叫了!
Well, you just bloody did!
没错 好吧 你吓到我了 我很害怕
Yeah well, you got me rolled. I'm very intimidated.
别让我们再来了
Don't make us come back again.
不是个个顾客都能满意
Not every customer is a satisfied customer.
你怎么来这了 亲爱的玛蒂?
What are you doing here, my dear Martine?
今晚有空吗?
What are you doing tonight?
今晚是艾迪的告别单身聚会
Tonight? Tonight is Eddie's stag do.
准备带他出去喝几杯 怎么了?
Taking him out for a drink. Why?
我给你找了个活干 特里
I've got a proposition for you, Terry.
给我找了个活?
A proposition?
聚会前能跟我 在运动员俱乐部碰个面吗?
Can you meet me at the Player's Club before you see the boys?
到时候我们再详谈
And I'll fill you in on the details.
那就九点见吧
Make it 9 o'clock.
[三周之前]
[3 weeks earlier]
- 早上好 盖儿 - 早上好 提姆
- Morning, Gale. - Good morning, Tim.
去顶楼? "上帝"召见?
Top floor? Summoned by the gods?
差不多吧
Something like that.
周末又出去风流了?
Got up to your new mistress this weekend?
听不懂你说什么 我可是已婚男人
I don't know what you're talking about, I'm a married man.
你觉得我看起来怎么样?
What do you think, am I presentable?
领带好像有些不妥 亲爱的
Not sure about the tie, darling.
这是什么? "和平友爱"?
What's this? "Peace and Love"?
这种东西太多的话 我们可就都失业了
Too much of that nonsense and we're both out of our job.
迈克.阿卜杜.麦里克自称迈克.X
Michael Abdul Malik. Calls himself Michael X,
根据他的美国老乡马尔科姆.X起的名字
in homage to Malcolm X, his American counterpart.
社会快报想让我们相信这个迈克.X
The Pinko (socialist) press would have us believe this Michael X
是穷人和被压迫阶级的领袖
is a crusading champion of the poor and oppressed.
简直是黑人版的侠盗罗宾汉
And the black Robin Hood of Notting Hill.
有钱人 白人贵族 以及许多名流都会在他那载跟头
The richer, whiter and more famous, they will all fall over him
其实他是个臭名昭著的地主 毒品贩子
The truth is, he's a slum landlord, a drug dealer
拉皮条的 几年前就该进监狱了
and a vicious pimp who should have been in prison years ago.
布朗先生 你是不是向我的黑人兄弟姐妹们收高价的房租?
Are you not charging outrageous rents to my brothers and sisters, Mr. Brown?
我和你的房东朋友卢.伍格收的价钱是一样的
I'm charging the same as your slum-lord friend Lew Vogel.
看你那破房子 一周10磅太贵了
Ten quids a week is too much for these shitholes.
你知道吗
You know,
我一直想找个叫布朗的白人打打交道.
I always wanted to meet a white man by the name of Brown.
知道这是什么吗? 这是个锁奴隶的颈圈
You know what this is? It's a slave collar.
你们白人就让我的祖先们戴着这个
And a white man made my mothers and fathers wear this
让他们屈从于你们
to bend them to his will.
你会屈从于我吗 布朗先生?
Can I bend you to my will, Mr. Brown?
你现在有条老实的狗了 迈克
You sure got a faithful dog now, Michael.
迈克 我觉得我们没有任何赢的希望
Michael, I don't think we should get our hopes up here.
绑架 虐待
Kidnappning, extortion,
你对这个布朗干的这些
assault on this man Brown here,
再加上你的前科 根据法律 我想...
as well as your previous problems with the law, I mean...
我得说你恐怕得坐10到20年的牢
You could be looking at 10 to 20 years, I'd say.
我可不觉得 我比白人想得更聪明 更会保护自己
I don't think so. I am smarter and better protected than whitey thinks.
全体起立
All rise.
看起来 迈克.X之所以能逃脱牢狱之灾
It seems Michael X has managed to keep himself out of jail
是因为他手里有些艳照 涉及某位 皇室成员
by threatening to release damning photographs of a certain...royal personage.
在我们插手之前 警察不会轻举妄动
Until we get our hands on these snaps, the police can't move.
检察院也不会...
The public prosecutor won't move...
而移民局则视而不见
and the home office doesn't want to know.
有人亲眼看见这些照片了吗?
Has anyone actually seen these photographs?
是的 但是现在我不能...
Yes, but at the minute I'm not at liberty...
透露他是谁
to say who that person is.
我们已经全程监控 迈克.X有一段时间了
We've had Michael X under surveillance for quite a while.
他在劳埃银行有个保险箱...
He keeps a safe deposit box at the Lloyd's Bank...
在玛丽伯恩路
in Marylebone.
我们相信照片就存放在那里
We believe that's were the photos are located.
看起来一目了然
Seems straightforward enough.
我会带一队人去这家银行
I'll send a team into this bank
把他保险箱清空
and take whatever he's got in this safe deposit box.
这些都得是最高级机密
That would have to be sanctioned at the highest level,
你不能那么做
and that's not going to happen.
明白你的难处了?
Do you see our problem?
军情五处和六处必须与此无关
There can be no connection to 5 or 6.
那你就是让我想个主意
So you want me to come up with something
可以不把任何人扯进来
devoid any accountability for anyone.
我们会适当地给你意见 提姆
We'd welcome suggestions, Tim.
如果出了什么岔子 我猜黑锅得我来背?
And if it all goes pear-shaped (wrong), I assume it's my arse on the line?
你年轻 有野心 提姆 这是大展身手的好机会
You're young and ambitions, Tim. A chance to make a name for yourself.
谢谢您 长官
Thank you, Sir.
请留步 小姐 能跟您说句话吗?
Excuse me, madam, miss. Can I have a word?
可以
Yes.
- 您从哪回来? - 摩洛哥
- Where have you been? - Morocco.
- 我得检查您的内衣 - 请便
- I'll have to check your underwear. - Be my guest.
- 我们找到要找的东西了 - 找到什么了?
- We found what we're looking for. - Found what?
你们在找什么?
What were you looking for?
提姆 谢天谢地!
Oh Tim, thank God!
我遇到麻烦了
I'm in a spot of bother. (I've got problems)
- 最近在忙什么呢? - 没啥 你呢?
- What have you been up to? - Nothing much. You?
我最近去了趟摩洛哥
I was in Morocco recently.
- 出差还是去玩? - 兼而有之吧
- Business or pleasure? - Bit of both.
这酒我请客
Drinks are on me.
那么 我们就整晚坐在这里聊天?
So, we're gonna sit here all night, making small-talk?
我了解你 特里 我也了解你的搭档
I know you, Terry, and I know your mates (friends).
你们一直想找个大买卖做
You've always been looking for the big score,
赚的钱购花一辈子的那种
the one that makes sense of everything.
- 我有你们想要的 - 什么?
- I have it for you. - What?
- 一家银行 - 一家银行...抢银行?
- A bank. - A bank...as in robber?
关于银行你了解什么?
What would you know about a bank?
我现在的男友是个做生意的
I've been seeing this guy who runs his own business.
保安系统
Security systems.
下个月 他们要在玛丽伯恩路某银行 装一套新的报警系统
Next month, they're installing new alarms in a bank at Marylebone.
好像是火车曾经...
Seems like the trains have been...
干扰到保险库的报警系统
setting off the trembler alarms in the vault
所以他们只好换掉
and they've had to turn them off.
那么一周内 他们就不会有警报
So for a week or so, they won't have any.
他为什么要告诉你?
Now why would he tell you all this?
我们拿这事儿开玩笑来着
We were having a laugh about it.
他说 如果伦敦一半的贼知道了这个消息会怎样
Imagine if half the villains in in London knew about this, he said.
我想 我就认识伦敦一半的贼
And I thought, I know half the villains in London.
我和其中一些人一起长大的
I grew up with some of them.
听着 我们几个是干过点儿
Look, me and my mates have been involved in the odd bit of
违法乱纪的事
skullduggery (criminal acts).
你能想象我们
Can you see us tooled up,
举着枪在银行里的样子吗?
taking on a bank like the (Jesse) James gang?
这不是让你们拿枪指着收款员威胁
This isn't about waving a waterpistol at a cashier's head.
而是进到放保险箱的地下室里
This is about getting into the basement where the deposit boxes are.
见不得人的现金和珠宝 偷它们很安全
Hidden, secret wealth. Money and jewels, they're safe to steal,
- 因为失主不敢声张 - 哦 不不不
- 'cause people won't report it. - Oh, no no no.
你不能在这谈论这些
You can't talk about this here.
这是绝无仅有的机会 特里
It's a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity, Terry.
我们不能错过它
We can't pass it up.
我没想到今晚你会跟我说这些 玛蒂
I didn't expect this from you tonight, Martine.
你想我会说什么?
What did you expect?
我得想想
I'll have to think about it.
最好赶去告别单身聚会吧
You better get off to your stag party.
谢谢你请我喝酒
Thanks for the drink.
艾迪说他哥哥邀请你参加婚礼了
Eddie tells me his brother invited you to the wedding.
- 去吗? - 到时候见
- Are you going? - I'll see you there.
- 堪培利酒加苏打水 不加冰 - 好的 先生
Can I get a Campari and Soda, no ice? - Yes, sir.
谢谢你
Thank you.
提姆你觉得怎么样?
Well, Tim sweety, what do you think?
- 他会同意吗? - 也许
- Is he offering? - Maybe.
干杯 美女
Cheers, gorgeous.
- 要进来吗? - 我不知道 太晚了
- So you're coming in? - I don't know, it's late.
得像个乖小孩儿一样按时回家?
Do you need to run home like a good little boy?
我猜还有点儿时间
I guess I've got time.
- 你到底是干嘛的? - 什么都干
- What exactly do you do? - Bit of this, bit of that.
你怎么认识哈蒂姆的?
How did you and Hakim meet?
我去年春天在洛杉矶遇到哈蒂姆
I met Hakim in Los Angeles last spring.
他当时一边为一个黑人蒙台梭利学校筹钱
He was rasing money for a black Montessori school
一边写他的传记
and writing his life's story.
那是多么奇妙的生活啊
And what an extraordinary life it has been.
那本书叫做 "死里逃生 迈克.X与我"
The book is called "From the Dead Level, Malcolm X and Me."
我读了手稿 哈蒂姆是个诗人
I've read the manuscript. Hakim is a poet.
代表黑人灵魂的声音
The voice of the black soul.
一个朋友下周会办活动
A friend is throwing a thing next week
庆贺哈蒂姆新书出版
to celebrate the launch of Brother Hakim's book,
你们都可以去
and you are all invited.
哈蒂姆 再多跟我们讲讲你的书
Hakim, tell us more about your book.
是讲出生在美国的黑人
It's about being born black in America.
你们谁能想象作为 一个黑人出生是什么感觉?
Can any of you imagine what it is like to be born a black man in this world?
你们当中又有哪个白人女人能想象
Can any of you white women imagine what it would be like
在这个世界生个黑人孩子的状况?
to bring a black baby into this world?
晚上好 先生
Good evening, sir.
你疯了吗? 为什么要讨论这个?
What, you freakhead? Why are we even having this conversation?
我们不是--
We're not--
你们的啤酒
Here's your beer.
我们不是抢银行的料
We are not bankrobbers.
也许这正能让我们脱身
Maybe that's why we could get away with it.
这不是在犯傻吗?
It's a bit daunting, isn't it?
你知道什么让我更害怕吗?
You know what scares me more?
整天这样混吃等死地活着
Living and dying with nothing to show for it.
知道莫扎特写成 第一首小步舞曲时几岁吗?
You know how old Mozart was when he composed his first minuet?
- 不知道 - 5岁 5岁! 小步舞曲!
- No. - Five. Five! A fucking minuet!
你怎么知道那是真的 特里?
And how would you know that fact, Terry?
那个脱衣舞女屁股上的纹身 加文
Because it's tattooed on that stripper's arse, Kevin.
我怎么知道的重要吗?
What the fuck's it matter how I know?
你没抓住重点 加文
It's a fact and you're missing the point, Kev.
我想说的是
What I'm trying to say is,
我们胡混日子 然后不再...
we stop fucking about and stop...
注意形象
picking the shit from under our fingernails.
别说了 12点方向有警察
Shtum (quiet), lads. Coppers at 12 o'clock.
妈的...
Damn...
你们两位亲自来有何贵干?
What are you two doing here, personally?
我以为你早就不跑腿儿了 杰里
I thought you were way past being a bagman, Jerry.
你的合伙人 索尼娅.波恩给她的妓院提价了
Your associate Sonia Bern has raised prices at that knocking shop of hers.
- 从100磅提到了120磅 - 你想怎样?
- ?20 quid up from a ?00. - And your point?
水涨船高 老兄
A rising tide lifts all ships, mate.
我想有人欠我们钱了
I think we are owed some money.
- 因为即使是索尼娅开的也会被搜捕 - 对 你们会那么做的吧?
- Cause even Sonia's can be raided. - Yeah, you would do that, wouldn't you?
你们会坐杀鸡取卵的事的
You'd kill the goose that lays you golden eggs.
那么做不是很傻吗?
Wouldn't that be dumb, would it?
然后又一次众人皆知警察很蠢了
But then again, everyone knows coppers are dumb.
现在你们可以为我做一件事
Now you can do one thing for me.
让你的人别再来我的夜总会
You stop your collegues from having their boys night out in my clubs.
他们吵吵闹闹的 还想要免费的口交
They're loud, they're lewd (horny) and they expect free oral sex.
你知道吗 真恶心 我的天 他们大部分人已经成家了
You know what, that's disgusting. My, most of them have families.
我们会让世界清净的
We'll pass the word along.
卢 告诉贪心的小警察们...
Lew, you tell your greedy little bobbies (cops)...
让他们另想法子赚外快
to find their perks (extra income) elsewhere.
别来惹我
No one is going to bother me.
我的后台能让所有这些人垮掉
My patrons could have a lot of these wank-cockers cut out of pasture.
但是 还是给他们点儿甜头少生是非比较好
Well, I'd say, spread the wealth around and keep the peace.
最多每周5磅
Five quid a week extra.
- 也就值这些了 - 我会告诉他们的
- It's all it's worth. - I'll pass it on.
- 佐斯德尔 - 厄科特
- Drysdale. - Urquhart.
佐斯德尔勋爵 在开始前 我请你喝一杯吧?
Lord Drysdale, can I offer you a drink before your session?
你真好 索尼娅
Very kind of you, Sonia.
- 能见到你很开心 - 我也是 厄科特 我也是
- Good to see you. - As well, Urquhart, as well.
乖宝贝儿
Good girl.
再紧点儿! 对 真是个乖宝贝儿
Tighter! Yes, that's a good girl.
- 一切顺利吗? - 顺利
- Everything okay? - Yeah.
[恭喜 艾迪 & 英格丽]
[Congratulations Eddie & Ingrid]
大点儿声
Louder.
再大点儿声!
Louder!
快来
Come on.
我们想看你们接吻
We want a kiss, what's wrong with you?
- 我做不到 - 快来...
- I just can't. - Come on...
快吻她
Give her a snogging (kiss), babe.
你们好啊
Hello.
你之前上杂志了?
So you were in a magazine the other day?
堪培利酒 沙滩广告 挺好的
The Campari ad on the beach. Nice.
很久以前了 我早就不做模特了
Must have been an old one, I'm not modeling any more.
为什么 你还是很迷人
I don't know why. You're still a knockout.
- 你现在干嘛呢 戴夫? - 我?
- What are you doing these days, Dave? - Me?
拍点儿电影 情色的 你懂吧
A bit of film work. Extra, you know.
你呢 加文? 我看见你还在拍照
And you, Kevin? You're still snapping, I see.
婚礼照片?
The wedding photos?
不不 这只是帮家里人拍照
No no, these are just photos for the family.
我现在做时尚 时尚和办护照
Fashion is my game. Fashion and passports.
- 还有帮变态照相 - 谢谢 戴夫
- And the odd snap of a wayward husband. - Thank you, Dave.
考虑结果如何 伙计们?
So, what's the verdict, boys?
我们感兴趣
We're interested.
我们应该先去那地方看看
First thing we should do is take a look at the place,
观察观察
suss (check) it out.
- 也许先租个保险箱 - 我已经租好了
- Maybe open a box of our own. - I've already done that.
明天我们就可以去看看
We can go and have a look tomorrow.
那就定明天
Tomorrow it is.
注意 伙计们
Heads up, lads.
- 她真可爱 是你小女儿啊 - 她睡着了
- She's adorable, your little one. - She is off.
你的大女儿也长得如花似玉
And what a gorgeous flower girl your eldest made.
谢谢你 卡瑟琳
Thanks. Catherine.
我真嫉妒你
I do envy you.
- 加文 想跳支舞吗? - 没问题 来吧
- Kev, you want to dance? - Yeah, come on.
见到你们大家真好
It was lovely to see you all.
- 回头见 - 回头见
- Ciao. - Ciao.
- 都好 伙计 - 都好
- All right, mate. - All right.
她羡慕我... 她在说反话吗?
She envies me... She's being sarcastic?
我觉得她的意思是 钱买不来我们的感情
I suppose what she meant was, money can't by what we have.
你从前没跟她约会过?
Didn't you use to go out with her?
没有 亲爱的 那是加文
No love, that was Kevin.
他那时很喜欢她
He had this big thing for her.
- 你没喜欢? - 没
- And you didn't? - No.
我喜欢的是你 一见钟情
I love me and you, love at first sight.
嗯 对...
Oh yeah...
我记得那天晚上 你和朋友奥德利在一家迪斯科
I remember that night, you were with your mate Audrey at that disco.
我看到了这个穿铅笔裙的含苞待放的女孩儿
I saw this gorgeous little bum in a pencil skirt
然后我就想 哦 我终于找到了
and I thought: "Oh, I've gotta have that."
而奥德利明显醉了 所以我拉走了你
But Audrey surely already had blows, so I pulled you.
她喝了不少
Cheeky sod.
爸爸 爸爸 来和跟我跳舞 快来 爸爸
Daddy, daddy, come and dance with me. Come on, dad.
别碰我
Hands off me.
早上好
Good morning.
我想看下我的保险箱
I'd like to access my safe deposit box, please.
- Martine Love L-O-V-E - 当然 女士
- Martine Love. L-O-V-E. - Certainly, madam.
- 你是个演员 对吗? - 对
- You're an actor, right? - That's right.
我曾经帮您拍过几部电影 伍格先生
I did a couple of films for you, Mr. Vogel.
嗯 对
Yeah, right.
你都演什么了?
So what are these films you're in?
别提这些了
Forget about it.
说吧
Go on.
技术上来讲 用你们的话说叫...
Technically, it's what you'd call...
色情片
pornography.
- 你开什么玩笑? - 我没有
- You're joking? - No.
这么说你在街上乱逛的时候
So you've been going around town with a
裤子里一直带着你那12寸的谋生工具?
12 inch mutton dagger hanging down your pants?
这没什么丢人的
That's nothing to be ashamed of.
不错啊
Nice.
假的
Fake.
为周末的豪华晚宴准备的
For the posh party at the weekend.
就是这 至少可以用
This is the one. The lease is available.
终于好了
Finally.
- 我看起来帅吗? - 并不是你最帅的样子 戴夫
- How do I look? Good? - Not your best, Dave.
我们开始吧
Here we go.
你是怎么搞到内部消息的 玛蒂?
So how come you've got the inside note on this place, Martine?
她相好的是开保安公司的
She knows this bloke, runs a security company.
相好的? 是认真的吗? 你们会结婚吗?
Bloke? Is it serious? Are you getting married?
他已经结婚了 好男人都结婚了
He is married. All the best ones are.
我们开始吧
Here we go.
银行就在玛丽伯恩路和贝克街的拐角处
Marylebone Road and Baker Street, on the corner here is the bank,
隔壁是那家炸鸡店 接着是189号塞克商店
next door is the Chicken Inn, and at 189, Le Sac.
在后面是家地下停车场
In the back is an underground car park
直接连到商店的地下室
with direct access to the shops' basements.
我们可以从格伦特沃兹街开进去...
We can pull in here from Glentworth Street...
进到停车场
into the car park
在那里装卸 而外面不会有人察觉
for dropoffs and pickups without being seen from the street.
我们得从商店地下室凿一个隧道
We'll dig a tunnel from the basement of the shop
从炸鸡店下面通过 然后出口直接到达保险库
under the Chicken Inn and pop up in the safe deposit vault.
我有个问题
I've got a question.
我们知道怎么挖地道吗?
What do ourselves know about digging tunnels?
不知道
Nothing.
但是我知道有个人会挖
But I know a man who does.
- 你觉得怎么样 班巴? - 我觉得怎么样?
- So what do you reckon, Bambas? - What do I reckon?
我觉得我认识你们 但我不认识她
I reckon I know you guys, but I don't know her.
别担心玛蒂 她靠得住
Don't worry about Martine, she's solid.
我们从小一起长大
We go way back.
特里 你从前是闯出过些名堂
Terry, you have been up to some mischief in your time
但是这是个惊天动地的大事儿 朋友
but this, this is serious shit, my friend.
你不觉得有点儿悬吗?
Don't you think it's a little out of your league?
也许我们该开始讨论第一步怎么做了
Maybe it's time to step up to the first division.
保险库下面会有一层混凝土
There's going to be reinforced concrete under the vault.
我们得搞到焊枪 电钻 发电机
We're going to need a thermic lance, a jackhammer, a generator,
照明 绳索 电缆 所有的设备
lights, ropes, cables, the works.
我们想进银行得先挖40英尺(13米)
It's about 40 feet (13m) of digging before we're under the bank.
我们可以从坎登城雇些人挖 (Camden Town 时为伦敦贫民区)
We can hire some Micks (Irishmen) from Camden Town to do the digging
你太有才了 戴夫
That's brilliant, Dave.
为什么我们不再帮他们买上保险呢?
Why don't we just pay their national ensurance contributions?
那样你就穿得上你的汤米牌螺纹西装了
And then you have to get on your Tommy Nutter suit.
- 看这边 迈克 再来一张 - 看这边
- This way, Michael. One more shot. - This way.
谢谢你 很不错
Thank you, that was great.
- 你有什么计划? - 我要回特立尼达了...
- What are your plans? - I am returning to Trinidad...
去解救我的兄弟姐妹们
to liberate my brothers and sisters
把他们从英国殖民者的奴役下解放出来
from the enslavement of the British colonialists.
那些对你提出的控诉怎么办? 你怎么离开英国?
What about the charges you are facing? How can you leave England?
他们都是骗子和懦夫
They are liars and cowards.
如果他们有任何不利于我的证据 但是他们害怕我
If they had anything against me but their fear of me,
我已经被审讯和关押过了
I'd be tried and jailed.
回见 班巴
See you later, Bambas.
我们需要有个人出面做这些
But we gonna need a front man on this,
一个可以正式租下那个店面做生意的人
someone who can sign the lease on the shop and looks the business.
我认识一个 盖尔.斯纳 自称"上校"
I know someone, Guy Singer. Calls himself "The Major".
但那是他胡吹的
But that's a lot of bollocks,
优雅的白人口音可帮他应付紧急场面
He has got this white posh accent if anyone comes nosing about.
胳膊下面好像有点紧?
A bit tight under the arms, dont you think?
这是传统款式 先生
Traditional fit, sir.
胳膊举不过头顶
One can't raise ones arms above one's head.
这样就不会养成任何举手投降的习惯了
It tends to inhibit any impulsive acts of surrender.
我马上就回来 先生
I'll be right back, sir.
你怎么会来这?
What on earth are you doing here?
给你找了单生意做 盖尔 你会感兴趣的
Got a bit of business for you here, Guy. You'll be tempted.
坐下 亲爱的
Sit down, luv.
你们想干嘛?
What do you think you're doing?
找辆车试开一下
Taking the E (Jaguar E-Type) for a test drive.
告诉你老板 想拿回他的货可以
Tell your boss, he can have his inventory back
先把 基索先生的债还了
when he settles Mr. Jessul's debt.
而且最好快点儿
And it'd better be soon
不然我们会来敲碎他的膝盖
or we'll be back to tap through his kneecaps.
如果我是你们俩 我会找份新工作
If I was you two, I was looking for another job.
亲爱的
Lovely.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
那么 快说 出了什么事儿? 怎么会周一晚上来顿浪漫晚餐?
So, come on then, what don't I know? Romantic dinner on a Monday night?
呃...亲爱的
Look honey,
接下来一两周我的工作时间可能会有些不一样 所以...
I'm going to be working some strange hours over the next week or two, so...
别问我会去做什么 因为我不想对你撒谎
don't ask me what I'm doing, because I don't want to lie to you.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
那个...
Look...
因为车卖不出去给我们带来了点儿麻烦
All llife I've caused us a few problems with all these cars aren't selling
我要做的就是努力全身而退
All I was trying to do is get ahead of the game.
- 我要做的事情会帮我们解决这些问题 - 坏事
- This thing's gonna put us there. - Wicked.
- 是的 - 好吧
- Yeah. - Yeah.
我们可以去个更好的地方
And a better place.
我这么做都是为了我们好
It's for all of us.
为了你和孩子们
For you and the kids.
那你要我怎么担心你 特里?
And how afraid do I have to be, Terry?
也许你最好搬去你阿姨家住
It'd be the best smart thing if you wanted to stay with your aunt,
以防万一出了什么岔子
in case things turn out cursed, that is.
说定了 我从特立尼达回来之前 你照看好我的姑娘们 分你25%的利润
So, we are settled. 25% to run my girls till I return from Trinidad.
好的 你放心吧
It's all right, you don't have to worry.
我会像照顾自己的一样照顾你那些雏儿们的
I'll look after your little flock of birds like they were my own.
别忘了她们不是你的就好
As long as you remember they are not your own.
卢 我回特立尼达期间
Lew, while I'm back in Trinidad,
我可以帮你运些大麻之类的
I can arrange for shipment of some high grade gunja (weed, marihuana).
不感兴趣
Not interested.
你想听听我的意见吗?
You want my opinion?
所有这些毒品都造成了...
All these drugs are responsible for...
这个国家里现在年轻人的堕落
the moral decay of this countries' young.
淫荡 情色 永无休止的放荡淫乱
Smut, smut and more smut. (pornography, dirt)
那才是我最感兴趣的地方
That's my special area of interest.
你该考虑考虑
You should think about it.
你在这些东西上能赚不少钱
With these goodies you can make a lot of dough (money),
更别说是你还有警察做靠山
especially the police in your pocket.
我已经尝到甜头了
I am paying enough pung as it is, (weed, here: money)
也许没有你捐给他们的那么多
but probably not as much as you're donating
特批离开我们国家
to be permitted to leave our fair shores (the country).
才不是呢! 我手上有很特别的东西 我不用掏钱行贿任何人
Not a shilling! I have something so special, I don't need to pay anyone.
你手上到底有什么 迈克?
And what would that be, Michael?
很抱歉 卢
Sorry, Lew.
好吧
Well.
不管是什么我希望你把它保存好
Whatever it is, you can't be buggered. I hope you're keeping it safe.
没问题 它非常安全 保存在你推荐的地方
Yes, as safe as it can be. In a place that you recommended.
transcript by r o g a r d
- 你迟到了 - 对不起
- You're late. - Sorry.
这是"上校" 盖尔.斯纳上校
This is the Major. Major Guy Singer.
我们人全了
Final member of our team.
我不认识这个人 你是谁?
I don't know this man. Who are you?
不关你事
None of your business.
这里没有秘密 "上校"是个老骗子
No secrets around here. The Major is a con artist.
通常对老寡妇下手
Usually elderly widows.
你没必要说这些
There's no need to bring that up.
现在他是塞克商店的新任老板
Now he's the official new owner of Le Sac.
专售高级女士手袋以及其他
Handbags and leather accesories for the discerning lady.
很好
Nice.
我告诉规划局办公室我得重新装修
I told the district planner's office about the remodelling.
他们把上下水 煤气 和电力系统图纸给了我
They gave me the specs for the sewage, drainage, gas and power lines.
让我们从这根管子开始
Lifted our take to miss that lot (a pipe).
这是干嘛用的?
What's this for?
那是热枪 用来穿透混凝土和切断钢筋
That is the thermic lance. It cuts through concrete and metal.
我们真的这么做了 对吗? 我觉得我们热血沸腾大干一场了
We're doing this, right? I mean, we're bloody going for it.
让我们看看这东西能干嘛
Let's see what this thing can do.
好主意 加文 来个示范 班巴
Good idea, Kev. Give us a demonstration, Bambas.
好的 拿着它 握住 这么拿
Ok, hold this. Hold it. Here.
加文 去氧气筒那边
Kevin, go stand over there by the oxygene.
我们开始吧
Here we go.
把它关上!
Turn it off!
关掉! 关掉! 关掉!
Off! Off! Off!
不能这么干
Not good.
这些人知道他们在干嘛 对吧?
They know what they're doing, these people, do they?
相当明确 职业罪犯
Absolutely. Professional criminals.
最糟的情况是什么?
What's the worst case scenario?
他们被抓了 然后去坐牢
They get caught and go to jail.
绝对不可能跟我们扯上关系
No possible connection to us.
跟你混在一起这个模特呢?
What about this model you're screwing?
你答应了她什么条件?
What promises have you made to keep her in line?
绝对没有问题
None that can't be broken.
是这样 她已经跟银行扯上了关系
Look, she's already tied to the bank operation.
一旦出了什么问题
If things do go belly up (go wrong)
剪断这一条线就可以了
it'll only take one cut to sever the knot.
盖儿.本森干嘛呢?
What's Gale Benson up to?
我相信她正用潜入迈克.X的老巢
I believe she's working her way into Michael X's inner sanctum.
能请你在这本书上签个名吗? 我终于让他们见面了
Could you sign that book, please? I've got them finally together.
爸爸!
Daddy!
我很高兴你还是来了
I am so glad you decided to come.
这是我父亲里昂.普路基勋爵
This is my father, Sir Leonard Plugge.
能见到盖儿的新朋友总是让我很高兴
Always happy to meet Gale's new friends.
她的新名字是海勒吉米加
Her new name is Halekimga.
这是我们名字的变位合称
It's an anagram of the letters of our names:
哈蒂姆和盖儿
Hakim and Gale.
- 那你的名字是? - 哈蒂姆 哈蒂姆.加摩尔
- And your name is? - Hakim. Hakim Jamal.
没错
Right.
不好意思...
Excuse me...
你好啊 美女
Hello, gorgeous.
那个作者在哪?
So, where's the author?
他在那边 给他的杰作签名
He's over there, signing his masterpiece.
你们不如这周末回家坐坐
Why don't you both drop by the house this weekend
把加摩尔先生介绍给你妈妈?
and introduce Mr. Jamal to mother?
对不起 爸爸 我们不能
Sorry daddy, can't do that.
我们会去岛上待一段时间
We're popping (going) on time for the islands for a while.
- 我帮你拿点儿喝的吧 - 希望你的书能畅销
- Let me get you a drink. - Good luck with your book.
- 那你看过他的这本书? - 你开什么玩笑
- So you've read this book of his? - You must be joking.
对 你很可能在卧底
Right. You're probably undercover,
调查黑人势力对英式生活的威胁
spying on Black Power's insidious threat to the British way of life.
呃 有意思
Oh, that's very funny.
告诉我 你在做的那件小事儿顺利吗?
Tell me, is that little enterprise still shipshape (going well)?
我们按部就班 提姆
We're currently on schedule, Tim.
我们这周五下午就接手那家商店
We're taking over the shop on Friday afternoon.
我知道搞砸了我就孤立无援了
I know if this stuffs up I'm in poo poo land.
(I know that I'm in serious trouble if this goes wrong)
一辆蓝色搬运车停在门口
We have a blue Transit van that's just pulled up.
车身写着 "克莱希建筑队"
"Clacy Builders" on the side.
有个男的进了那家商店
And we have one man entering the shop.
来给塞克商店装修的
Construction crew, for Le Sac.
[店铺易主 即将开业]
[Under new management. Reopening soon]
我有个问题
I've got a question.
我们挖出来的土怎么解决?
What do we do with all the dirt we're gonna dig out of the hole?
这问题已经解决了 戴夫
That's all been worked out, Dave.
我们会在那边在挖个洞 就把土放进那里 完毕
We'll dig another hole over there and put in in that. Over.
要想在银行周一早上开门前完工
If we're to get the job done before the bank opens on Monday morning,
我们最好赶紧开始干活
we better get a wriggle (move) on.
想挖第一下吗 玛蒂?
Want to do the honours, Martine?
就这样 我们开工了
This is it, here we go.
小心你的指甲 玛蒂
Watch your nails, Martine.
很好 不错
Yeah, yeah.
让我们把这商店搞得天翻地覆吧
Let's get this store to rock.
- 这么吵 - 天啊! 这是怎么了?
- Some racket (noise) there is. - Bloody hell! What's going on?
戴夫 快 哥们儿
Dave, come on, mate.
戴夫 你歇会儿吧 我干会儿
Dave, you need a break. I'll take over.
多谢 上校
Cheers (thanks), Major.
小心
Heads up!
- 戴夫去哪了? - 不知道
- Where's Dave? - No idea.
你去哪了?
Where did you get to?
就去看看门有没有锁好
Just checking the door was locked.
当然锁好了 戴夫 我锁的
Of course it's locked, Dave. I locked it.
等下 有情况
Hang on. Look what we got here.
是个警察
This is a copper.
他不是要进去吧?
Christ, he's not going in there, is he?
- 我去看看 - 该死! 戴夫 回来
- I'll go. - Shit! Dave, Dave, get back.
- 我只是想去-- - 停! 先别干了!
- I only wanted-- - Stop! Hold it down!
有人在敲门 有人在敲门
Someone is knocking. Someone is at the door.
停 快停! 有人在店门口敲门
Stop, Stop! There's somebody at the door of the shop.
班巴!
Bambas!
班巴!停一下!
Bambas! Hold on!
有人在敲门
There's somebody at the door.
- 听着 我可以去 - 那是我的活
- Look, I don't want to go in. - It's my job.
警察
Coppers.
是条子
It's the old bill (police).
晚上好 你们在上夜班吗?
Good evening. You're working late?
日夜赶工 长官 我们要扩大店面
Around the clock, officer. Expanding our storage.
想全面翻新好增加收入--
Trying to complete renovations for the grand reopening--
如果你不介意 先生
If you don't mind, sir.
打扰一下?
Excuse me?
在下面用电钻呢?
You use a jackhammer down there?
对 您接到投诉了吗 长官?
Yeah. You heard some complaints, officer?
没错 从你们邻居那儿
Yeah, from some of your neighbours.
我们会尽量降低声音 好吗?
We'll try to keep it down, all right?
好吧
Right.
他们是怎么他妈的应付的?
How the hell did they talk their way out of that one?
提姆 我是奎恩
Tim, Quinn here.
刚才有个警察进了那家商店
We just had a copper going into the shop.
不知道干嘛 现在走了
Not sure why, but he's gone now.
解决了
All clear.
我们需要个把风的 在楼顶找个地方盯着
We need a lookout, someone on a roof somewhere.
- 我们有无线电对讲机 - 艾迪怎么样?
- We've got the walkie-talkies. - What about Eddie?
他人不错 我们可以信任他
He's a good lad, we can trust him.
不行 听着 我们不能再让任何人入伙了
No. Look, we're not cutting anyone else in.
我们不让他入伙
We won't cut him in on the loot.
最多把车让给他
We'll give him the car lot.
希望我没其他事情担心了
Hopefully I won't need that headache anymore.
- 天哪 又来 - 上去看看 上校
- My God, not again. - Get up there, Major.
蒙混过去!
Cover that up!
不是警察
It's not the coppers.
- 你好 有什么事吗? - 戴夫.史令叫的外卖
- Yes, can I help you? - Delivery for Dave Shilling.
- 送的什么? - 炸鸡和薯条
- And what is it? - Chicken and chips.
知道了...
I see...
- 史令先生叫的外卖 - 谢谢
- Takeaway for Mr. Shilling. - Thanks.
- 你开什么玩笑 - 我都快饿死了
- You can't be serious. - I was starving.
收音机在包里 还有望远镜和其他东西
Radio is in the bag, binoculars as well.
在楼顶有个小屋
There's a pension on the top floor of this building,
租了一周
paid for the week.
那有个梯子让你可以爬上去
There's a ladder that'll get you to the roof.
你是从利物浦来找工作的
You're in from Liverpool, looking for work.
我没有利物浦口音
I don't have a Liverpool accent.
那就别跟任何人说话 艾迪
Then don't talk to anyone, Eddie.
我到楼顶了 然后...
I'm up on the roof, and...
我找了个好地方
I've got a good view
各个方向都能看到 完毕
of all directions, over.
你到达指定位置了吗 "更夫"? 这里是总部 请确认
Are you in position, Nightjar? Command HQ here. Acknowledge.
是的 我到了 这里可以看到银行前门
Yeah, I'm in position. I can see the front of the bank,
玛丽伯恩路
Marylebone Road,
贝克街  所有的一切尽收眼底
Baker Street, I can see everything really well.
西面前门安全 盖尔 完毕
All clear on the Western front, Guy. Over.
- 不要叫名字 艾迪 - 对不起 戴夫
- No names, Eddie. - Sorry, Dave.
嘿 你个犯罪分子 我跟你说啥来的?
Aye, you delinquents. What have I told you?
别瞎侃
No idle chitchat.
对不起 提-- 完毕
Sorry, T-- Over.
该死...
Fuckin' hell...
精神点儿 先生们
Wakey wakey, gentlemen.
从现在起我来监视商店
I'll keep an eye on the shop from here on.
你们俩去格伦特沃兹街
You two go down to Glentworth Street.
看着停车场出口
Guard the parking garage exit.
好
Okay.
"更夫" 呼叫 有个家伙正从窗子向里看
Nightjar here, there's some fellow looking through the window.
等一下
Hang on.
等 等等 他要走了 他要走了
Wait, hang on. He's going. He's going.
好 他走了 完毕
Yeah, he's gone. Over.
收到  "更夫"  完毕 收线
Roger, Nightjar. Over and out.
我要去酒吧买包烟
I want to go to the pub, grab some more smokes.
你要带什么吗?
Do you want anything?
来包"海军"
A pack of Seniors.
给您 先生
There you go, sir.
两包"乐福门"
Two packets of Rothmans,
两包"海军"  再来8袋薯片
2 Senior Service and 8 bags of crisps.
好的
Okay.
你好 美女 一切顺利?
Hello, gorgeous. Are we still on track?
昨晚吓了一跳 有个警察进来了
We had a scare last night. The cops came round.
你能不能活动活动让这种事儿别再发生了?
Can't you pull rank and make sure it doesn't happen again?
不行 我们不能出手 我们隐身幕后 记得吗?
No, we can't show our hand. We're invisible, remember?
- 我希望我也是 - 你朋友特里怎么样了?
- I wish I was. - How about your friend Terry?
他打算把东西藏在哪?
Where is he planning to carve up the proceeds?
该死
Shit.
- 来杯啤酒 - 怎么了?
- A pint of ale, chief. - What's wrong?
我得歇会儿
I needed to take a break.
刚才跟谁聊天呢?
Who's that you've been talking to?
我没聊天 他想跟我搭讪
I wasn't. He was trying to chat me up.
这种事儿常有 你知道的
Does happen, you know.
- 是啊 - 给你
- Right. - Here you are.
- 谢谢 不用找了 - 谢谢
- Cheers. Keep the change. - Thank you.
那么 你在这干嘛? 你在跟踪我?
Now, what are you doing here? Are you following me?
不
No.
- 我只是想喝杯啤酒 - 那你好好享用吧
- I just wanted a pint. - Then enjoy it.
- 你好啊 盖儿 - 你去哪了?
- Hello, Gale. - Where have you been?
你对我们的朋友哈蒂姆印象不错啊 是吧?
You're rather impressed with our friend Hakim, aren't you?
我知道 纪律第一条:"不许掺杂儿女私情"
I know rule #1: "Don't get emotionally involved"
那并不代表我不能享受工作的乐趣
That doesn't mean I can't enjoy my work.
你是挺享受的
You certainly do.
不管怎样 你父亲对你和这些激进分子搅在一起有什么想法?
What does your father think of your consorting with these radicals anyway?
我们意见不太合
We are not amused.
当然了 如果他知道我到底在干什么
Of course, if he knew what I was really up to,
会心脏病发的
he would have a heart attack.
给你 信用卡和现金
Here you are. Credit cards and cash.
如果他手里真有照片和底片
If he does have copies of the photos and negatives there,
也肯定藏起来了
they will be hidden.
找到它们 销毁它们
Find them. Destroy them.
然后撤退
And then get out.
迈克.X 觉得他躲在特立尼达就安全了
Michael X thinks he's safe, tucked away in Trinidad.
如果我们这边成功了 那就不一样了
That will all change if we're successful here.
一定要记住 盖儿 他可是很阴险
Just remember, Gale: He's a nasty piece of work.
他是个疯狂的瘾君子 坏事做尽的皮条客 我知道他的老底儿
He's a crazy dope-smoking lunatic pimp extortionist, that's what he is.
一切顺利吗 "更夫"? 有没有什么情况要向我汇报?
Everything okay, Nightjar? Anything I need to know?
没有 一切顺利 伙计
Yeah, everything's all right, mate.
听着 我在这怎么撒尿?
Listen, what if I want to go for a pee up here?
我不知道 发挥你的想象力吧
I don't know. Use your imagination.
别用无线电 除非你看到警察 好吗?
Stay off the radio unless you see any old bill (police), all right?
好 没问题 如果我看见警察了 我会通知你的
Yeah, all right. If I see any old bill, I'll let you know.
晚点儿再说 完毕
I'll speak to you in a bit. Over.
嘿 班巴
Hey Bambas.
这些砖砌的是什么?
What's all this brickwork?
我不知道 图纸上没写
I don't know, it wasn't on the plans.
操!
Fuck!
特里? 操他妈的!
Terry? Fucking hell!
特里! 班巴!
Terry! Bambas!
特里 说话!
Terry, talk to me!
特里!
Terry!
我操..
Oh fuck..
特里 跟我说话!
Terry, talk to me!
- 你还好吗? - 我想是的 还好
- Are you all right? - I think so, yeah.
怎么了?
What happened?
地刚刚塌了
The floor just caved in.
该死的 特里 别吓唬我
Bloody hell, Terry. Don't do that to me.
- 我还以为你小命儿不保了 - 没错
- I thought you was a goner (dead). - Yeah.
给我拿盏灯 戴夫
Give us a light, Dave.
下面是什么?
What's down there?
- 是一大堆尸骨 - 你开玩笑吧
- It's a pile of skeletons. - You're joking.
希望他们不是上一帮来抢这个银行的劫匪
Let's hope they're not the last gang who tried to take this bank.
拉丁语 大概意思是:
Latin. Roughly translated:
仁慈的上帝 请宽恕我们的罪过
Lamb of God, forgive us our sins.
- 你真懂拉丁语? - 我上的是天主教学校
- You actually know Latin? - Catholic school.
让修女们一直头疼不已
The Bleeding Heart sisters of eternal misery.
日期挺有意思的 1665年
Interesting date. 1665.
你们都知道那年发生了什么 对吗?
You all know what year that was, don't you?
西汉姆联队上次夺冠?
The last time West Ham won the (F.A.) cup?
伦敦大瘟疫
It was the great plague of London.
这里一定是个墓穴
This must be a burial chamber.
他们抛尸的密室
A crypt where they dumped the bodies.
那么 如果这些人是得瘟疫死的
Well, if these poor bastards had the plague,
他们还可能是有传染性的
then they could be infectious.
我觉得不会 戴夫
I don't think so, Dave.
这个密室直通银行底下
This crypt goes all the way under the bank.
它给我们弄了条捷径
It'll put us in the vault quicker.
好 那我们就把它打通
Well, then we'll gonna do that.
混凝土
Concrete.
保险库的地面
Floor of the vault.
是拿回报的时候了
Time to get paid for all our work.
对
Right.
如果我们搞错了凿到那饭馆 就顺便吃点儿炸鸡和薯片
If we hit the restaurant by mistake, we'll be knee-deep in fried chicken.
砸的不是下水道我就满足了
I'll be happy if we don't hit the sewage.
你们这群家伙什么时候能挖到金库啊?
When are you guys going to hit the vault?
我在这冻得脚趾头都要掉了 完毕
I'm freezing my tits off up here. Over.
打仗的时候 士兵们会自慰
In the army, soldiers would pull on
来保持血液循环 试试这办法怎么样?
their puds (penises) to keep their blood flowing. How's that?
你待的是皇家白痴连队吗?
What regiment were you in, the Royal Corps of Wankers?
完毕
Over.
对 我们欢迎新队员 收到 完毕 收线
Yes, we welcome new members. Roger, over and out.
这里是紧急援助中心 请问您需要什么帮助?
Emergency operator. Which service do you require?
- 请帮我接警察局 - 正在帮您转接
- The police, please. - Putting you through.
这里是警察局 需要什么帮助吗?
Police here. Can I help you?
是的 我是汉姆的一个无线电报务员
Yes. I'm a HAM radio operator
我想我可能在无线电里监听到了一个银行抢劫行动
and I think I may be overhearing a robbery in progress.
我们打通了! 戴夫 把梯子拿过来
We're in! Dave, get the ladder.
我们歇会儿再进保险库
We're gonna move into the vault after we take a break.
等尘土散了的
Later when the fume's cleared out.
你开玩笑吧? 我们现在就进去
You're having a laugh, ain't you? Let's go in now.
戴夫 没有东西会长腿跑了 我在那上面几乎不能呼吸
Dave. Nothing's going nowhere. I can hardly breathe in there.
- "更夫" 你在吗? 完毕 - "更夫"在这 完毕
- Nightjar, are you there? Over. - Nightjar here, over.
我们进来了 完毕
We're in. Over.
什么 真在保险库里?
What, in the actual vault?
是的 真在保险库里 完毕
Yes, in the actual vault. Over.
太好了 太好了 真是个好消息 完毕
Great, great. That's great news. Over.
我们在休息 我们累屁了
We're taking a break. We're knackered (tired).
我得睡会儿觉
I need to get some sleep.
小睡一会儿 得让尘土散散 完毕
Getting a shut-eye (a nap). I want the fumes cleared out. Over.
你倒轻巧了 我的眼睛就像永远不用合上似的 完毕
Lucky you. My eyes are like **** stops. Over.
我们都能闻到钱的味道了 完毕
We can smell the money now. Over.
听着 那钱可能是你的上帝 但是不是我的 对吧?
Look, money may be your god, but it ain't mine, all right?
我想要的是热水澡加一杯热茶 完毕
I want a warm bath and a cup of tea. Over.
热茶会有的 再坚持下
You'll get your cup of tea. Just your odd time.
你倒轻巧了 我的眼睛就像永远不用合上似的 完毕
Lucky you. My eyes are like **** stops.
我们都能闻到钱的味道了
We can smell the money now.
之前我还给另外四个警察局打过电话...
I rang 4 other police stations before you,
但是没人把我当回事儿
but nobody took me sriously.
他们说这很可能是个恶作剧
They said it was probably a hoax.
这信号有多强 Addey先生?
How strong was the signal, Mr. Addey?
我看他们得在半径10英里以内
I'd say they were within a 10 mile radius.
在这个范围里的银行数都数不清
There must be a ton of banks in that area.
那你最后一听到他们通话是什么时候?
And when was the last time you picked them up?
他们已经安静了一个小时了
They've been quiet for about an hour.
把磁带在广播和电视上播出怎么样?
What about releasing the tapes to the radio and TV?
也许会有人分辨出声音?
Maybe somebody can recognize the voices?
不行 不
No, no.
如果让他们自己听见了 他们就会停止使用无线电了
If they hear themselves, they'll stop transmitting.
不能那样 我们得继续监听
No, we should keep listening.
也许他们会暴露他们在哪
Maybe they'll reveal where they are.
艾尔费 你在这和奥迪先生一起 我先回局里
Alfie, you stay here with Mr. Addey. I am going back to the station.
如果听到什么给我打电话
You call me if you hear anything.
嗨
Hi.
你差点儿吓得我尿裤子
You scared the piss out of me.
- 你干嘛呢? - 我睡不着
- What are you doing here? - I couldn't sleep.
对 我有点儿太紧张了..
Yeah, I'm a bit tingly (nervous) myself..
我只是必须得过来看看 我们的将来就在这些盒子里了
I just had to come and have a look. Our future is in those boxes.
那么 你打算怎么花你那份儿?
So, what are you going to do with your share?
人间蒸发 Martine Love 将不复存在
Vanish. Martine Love will cease to exist.
为什么 你以为你蒸发了就变成另一个人了?
Why, do you think if you vanish you'll become someone else?
至少不会有人知道我的过去
At least no one will know who I was.
为什么选加文和我? 你本可以找更厉害的贼
Why did you pick Kevin and me? You could have found better thieves.
看在过去的份儿上
For old times' sake.
肯定是为了你和加文的旧情
Must be old times you spent with Kevin,
跟我没关系
not me.
加文一直觉得我和他有过一段激情岁月
Kevin has it in his mind that we had this passionate affair.
事实上 我们只是
The truth is, it came down
吃过四次中国菜 上过一次床而已
to 4 chinese meals and a roll in the hay.
而且那是很久之前的事了
And that was a long time ago.
好吧
All right,
让我们开始赚钱吧
let's make some money.
看看这个!
Look at this!
看看这些现金
Look at all this cash.
太棒了!
Fantastic!
伙计们? 金条
Guys? Gold bars.
钻石 钻石!
Diamonds. Diamonds!
伙计们 进行到哪了?
Guys, what's going on?
你老婆是不是喜欢首饰?
How would your wife fancy a tiara?
说的太对了
Too bloody right.
拿着那些钱 那些现金
Get the gas. The gas.
看看 快拿着它
Look at it. Hold it.
- 翡翠 - 真像中了彩票
- Emerald. - It's like winning the lottery.
戴夫 帮我弄弄这个
Dave. Give us a hand with this one.
- 这盒子有什么特别的? - 是我的幸运数字
- What's so special about this box? - It's my lucky number.
都是你的了 我的可人儿
All yours, me lovely.
- 交给你啦 - 谢谢
- There you are. - Cheers.
该死的 你知道这是谁吗?
Holy shit. You know who that is?
这是Margaret公主
It's Princess Margaret.
特里 有没有什么捐给寡妇拍卖基金的?
Terry, anything for the widows and auctions funds?
- 这些够了吗? - 上帝保佑你 你真是太慷慨了
- Will that do? - God bless you, you're very generous.
听着 我们得分清主次
Look, we have to have some sort of system.
你们不知道什么能拿什么不能拿
You don't know what you are throwing or what you are keeping.
是的 但是我们知道钱长什么样儿
Yeah, but we know what money looks like.
我们不会把这些丢下 对吧?
We're not throwing that away, are we?
抢个银行到底需要多久?
How long does it take to rob a bank?
我们马上就要完活了 好吗?
We're just about to get this job done, okay?
更多的现金
More cash.
看看这个
Have a look at this.
不 没有
No, nothing.
还是什么也没有
Still nothing.
局长 我们需要做的是
Sergeant, what we need is something
打草惊蛇让那些劫匪使用无线电
that will motivate the robbers to go on air,
- 好找出他们在哪 - 说的对..
- give away their location. - Right..
等着鱼上钩吧
Bait to lure the fish.
不 他们没在那 他们没有联络
No, they are not there, not transmitting.
长官 他们没在那
They are not there, sir.
到下个银行去 2号车
Move to the next bank, unit #2.
目前为止没有任何进展 长官
We still get nothing, Sarge.
好吧 2号车 到下个地方去
Ok, unit #2, move to the next location.
天哪 有人收藏的...
My God, the stuff that some people collect...
你找到了什么 特里?
What have you got there, Terry?
- '47. - '47?
听起来是个不错的年份
Sounds like a good year to me.
快递过来
Will you pass it round?
来吧 特里 给我们也弄一瓶
Come on, Terry. Give us some.
很好
Got it.
接好了!
Catch!
哦!耶
Oi! Yeah...
给 上校
Here, Major.
等等
Get it down.
听着 伙计们 条子们来了
Listen fellows, they are onto you.
听清楚了 他们过来了 靠
Listen, they're onto you. - Fuck.
条子就在门口
Coppers are on your doorstep.
你说什么 更夫
Speak to me, Nightjar.
条子就在门口
Coppers are on your doorstep.
听着 冷静冷静 他们不会进来的
Listen. Hang on, hang on... they're not going in,
可他们也没打算走 等等 等等
but they are not going away. Wait, wait.
警官 我们刚听到他们通风报信了
Sergeant, we just heard the thieves' lookout
他们说银行外面现在有警察
say that there are police outside the bank right now.
哪家银行? 我还不清楚
- Which bank? - I haven't got a clue.
伦敦西区一半以上的银行 外面都有我们的巡逻队
We've got patrols outside half the banks in the West End.
仔细听着  我们要知道他们确切的位置
Keep listening, we need to pinpoint exactly where they are.
等等 先别动
Wait. Hang on.
伙计们 过来一辆黑色轿车 里面下来一个人
Guys, a black car just pulled up with some bloke.
他打算跟条子一起去前门
He's going up to the front door with the cops.
伙计们 他在用钥匙开门
Gyus, he is unlocking the front door.
他们要进去了 靠! 完毕
They are going in. Shit! Over.
哦 不 靠
Oh no. Shit.
金库在哪? 楼下
- Where is the vault? - Downstairs.
跟我来
Follow me.
好像没事
Looks fine.
你确定一切正常吧? 是的是的 一切正常
Are you sure everything is all right? Yes, yes, it is.
我想去里面看看 去跟打卡机说
- I want to look inside. - Tell the timelock.
明早才能开
Can't be opened until tomorrow morning.
好吧 反正抢的也不是我的银行
Well, it isn't my bank that's being robbed.
抱歉星期天早上还来打扰你 长官
Sorry for calling you on a Sunday morning, sir.
没什么 谢谢
- Not a problem... - Thank you.
伙计们 看来他们准备走了
Fellows, I think they are going away.
他们已经走了
They are gone.
我们得离开这 他们可能还会回来
We should get out of here. They could be coming back.
对 没错 我们得让艾迪知道
Yeah, right. We need to let Eddie know.
更夫?
Nightjar?
不!
No!
该死!
Fuck!
操 真该死
Shit. Fuck.
去他妈的
Shit. Shit.
你在么 更夫?
Are you there, Nightjar?
救护车现在在 贝克街的劳埃银行外面
The ambulance reports it's outside the Lloyd's bank on Baker Street.
更夫 你能听见我说话么?
Nightjar, can you hear me?
你是不是睡着了 更夫?
You got asleep, Nightjar?
该死...
Fucking hell...
更夫 你在不在?
Nightjar, are you there?
看 他老是不回答 肯定出事了
Look, if he's not picking up, something is wrong.
你说的没错
You're right.
所以 把所有的首饰和珠宝都拿走
So, grab all the cash and the jewels
然后他妈的离开这
and get the fuck out of here.
我们这些工具怎么处理?
What about our gear?
我们不能把这些东西留在这 会把条子引来的
We cant leave anything that might incriminate us.
如果有机会我们以后再回来处理
We come back for it if we can.
剩下那些保险箱呢?
What about all the other boxes?
别管那些 戴夫 把东西都装到袋子里然后我们走!
Doesn't matter, Dave. Put everything in a bag and lets go!
好吧 我们走 快!
All right, let's move it. Come on!
没有动静 长官 你确定?
- There's nothing here, Sarge. - Are you sure?
他们根本就没提到什么救护车
There's no mention of the ambulance.
没事了 走吧 2号车
Nothing. Move on, vehicle #2.
我们走! 总算搞定了
- Let's go! - Finally.
快 我们走
Come on, let's go.
那辆货车开走了 我们会跟着它的 完毕
The van is leaving. We will follow them. Over.
快拦下他们
Stop them as soon as possible.
开门!
Open the door!
我干了什么 长官? 把后门打开  快
- What have I done, guv'nor (boss)? - Open the back door, come on.
有人给了我50镑让我把这车开走
Some fella paid me 50 quid to pick up his van
然后停到希思罗机场去
and drop it at Heathrow airport.
上帝..
Jesus Christ...
车在哪? 计划变了
- Wher's the van? - Change of plan.
以防万一
For cautionary measure.
我安排了另一条路线
I've organised alternative transport.
为什么? 我们中没有一个人见过你的那位朋友
- Why? - None of us have met your boyfriend.
他很可能把我们都给卖了 包括你
(*He's all go to include you on the back) of the job.
那我们就完了
Could've set us up.
我简直热血沸腾
We bloody well pulled it off.
你可得好好算下这笔钱了 嘿 上校?
Done with military precision, hey, major?
既然我是财务总监
Now that I am fiscally secure,
我决定升自己做"上将"
I think I'll promote myself to "Colonel".
你知道我有什么打算么?
You know what I am going to do?
我打算给我妈买一栋新房子 那种带花园的
I'm going to buy my mom a new house. Something with a garden.
我觉得你可能会去哥本哈根  戴夫?
I thought you would be off to Kopenhagen, Dave?
我为什么要去哥本哈根? 所谓狗改不了吃屎
- Why would I go to Kopenhagen? - Heavy cock, sure hunt.
我猜我打算干吗? 如果我再多开一个保险箱
You know what I'll do? I'll chop off one more
就可以看到你的小弟弟在里面
and then I got one like your little pinkey (penis).
你是怎么找到这么个地方的 特里?
How did you find this place then, Terry?
我认识的一个朋友
A bloke and I used to run a...
在这里"揽活"(偷车然后售卖零件)
chop shop here (stolen cars sold in parts).
他现在在牢里
He's in the nick (jail) now.
你怎么可以失去控制权?
How could you lose control of the operation?
我以为你都搞定了
I thought you were on top of this thing.
长官 一切都按计划进行
Sir, it worked.
是他们干的 他们抢劫了金库
They did the job. They robbed the vault.
我们却不知道他们他妈的在哪
And we have no idea where the fuck they are.
你知道么 我刚刚有种不好的预感
You know, an ugly thought has just occured.
那个金库里全是钞票 珠宝 债券
Lots of money in that vault, juwelry, bonds.
我希望你跟你亲爱的没有对我说假话
You and your sweetie haven't cooked up something between you, I hope.
难道你觉得我会出卖你? 这可说不准
- You think I'd betray you? - There are precedence.
我以前的两个同事 现在就在该死的莫斯科
Two of our former colleagues now live in bloody Moscow.
希望别再节外生枝了
Let's hope they don't have another bidder.
她不会出卖我们的 她知道出卖我们会有什么下场
She won't cross us. She knows what we're capable of.
她怎么会知道我们他妈的是些什么人?
How does she even know who the hell we are?
我相信她一定会联系我们 如果她有点头脑的话
I'm sure she will contact me when she comes to her senses.
否则就相当于自寻死路
Going anywhere else would be a death sentence.
你最好祈祷她会这么想 艾福特
You better hope she does, Everett.
不然自寻死路的恐怕就是你了
Or it may be yours.
班巴 给你 这份是你的
Here you go, Bambas. That's your lot.
"激情过后不要急于冲凉 小雪花"
"Never washed after our magic moment. Snowflake."
嘿 戴夫 看这个
Hey, Dave. Look at this.
我在电视上见过这家伙 这个老变态
I've seen this bloke on the TV. The old perv (pervert).
我以前也见过他 他是个国会议员
I have seen this face before. He's an M.P. (member of parliament).
上帝...你知道他叫什么吗 老是带着那些白痴领结
Lord... whatshisname, you know. Always wears those poncey bow ties.
嗯 不过那张照片上没带
Well, on that picture he's not.
我相信这可能是你以前的作品 戴夫
I believe this is one of your old movies, Dave.
少来  加文
Piss off, Kev.
是时候提个建议了
Timely suggestion.
我觉得我应该拿着属于我的那份在
I believe I'll take my share and be on my way,
银行早上开门前离开
before the bank opens in the morning
然后就让条子们忙活去吧
and the shit hits the proverbial fan.
算我一个 盖尔
I'm with you, Guy.
别说我没提醒你
I don't have to remind you:
低调行事 别买跑车 班巴
Keep a low profile. No buying Aston Martins, Bambas.
我只会买一张回塞浦路斯的单程票
The only thing I'm buying is a one-way ticket back to Cyprus.
然后再也不会回来 我们应该再聚一次
- I'm never coming back. - We should have a reunion.
20年后 在索威烤肉店 嗯 不错 哥们 为了你
- 20 years, the Savoy Grill. - Yeah, right, maybe for you, Guy.
保持联络
I still wouldn't let us lot in.
班巴 再见了 伙计们
- Bambas. - Goodbye my friend.
好好照顾自己 哥们
Take care of yourself, mate.
上校
Major.
好运
Be lucky.
班巴
Bambas.
再见 老朋友
Goodbye, old chap.
好吧 发生了什么? 你们俩离开银行后就
Okay, what's going on? You two have been staring
一直不对劲
daggers at each other since we left the bank
怎么回事? 情侣吵架?
What is it? Lover's tiff (quarrel)?
我觉得玛蒂有什么事瞒着我们
I think Martine has got something to tell us.
等等 伙计们 那是玛格丽特公主
Hang on, pal. That's Princess Margaret.
天哪
Fuck me...
这些是从哪来的?
Where do these come from?
你知道这个保险箱里装的是什么 玛蒂
You knew the exact box this stuff was in, Martine.
你最好过来跟我们解释下 这到底是怎么回事
You'd better come clean and tell us what this is really about.
大概一个月前 我在希思罗被逮住了 因为一项毒品交易的指控
About a month ago I got busted at Heathrow on a drug charge.
这时有个人来跟我说 他会帮我搞定一切于是他帮我逃了出来
This guy I know said he would fix it to keep me out of jail,
代价是让我帮他一个小忙
if I do him a favour.
他知道我认识一些混混
He knew I knew some villains.
他想靠抢劫来发财
He wanted to set up a robbery to get these.
去他妈的!
Fucking hell!
就是你在运动员俱乐部碰到的那个人?
That would be the bloke you met in the Player's Club.
就是你说想泡你的那个家伙 是吧?
Same guy you said was trying to pick you up in the club, right?
没错 嗯 那他到底是什么人?
- Yeah. - Well, so who is he?
我们是在松布列罗俱乐部认识的
He's a guy I met at the Sombrero Club.
他替白厅的某些地下组织做事
He works for some shady outfit in White Hall.
哦 不 你该不是在说该死的军情五处? 或者6处?
- Oh no, no. You mean MI fucking 5? - Or 6?
我们很可能陷入大麻烦了玛蒂!
We could get seriously nicked here, Martine!
没 不会有事的
No, we couldn't.
提姆只想要118号箱子里的东西
All Tim wants is the contents of box 118.
协议是我们可以留下剩下的东西
The deal with him is, we get to keep everything else.
你居然相信这个?
And you believe that?
你居然相信这些我们连见都没见过的家伙
You put your trust in some prick we've never even met.
你骗了我们  玛蒂!
You lied to us, Martine!
我们从一开始就被蒙在鼓里
We were sitting ducks right from ther start.
真是非常感谢你
Thank you very much.
你觉得你被指控贩毒并被捕只是一个巧合么
You think it's a coincidence that you get busted for drugs
还有你那认识的那个什么提姆 碰巧有个抢劫银行的计划?
and your Tim just happens to have a plan to rob a bank?
不是这样
This can work out.
我们只要给了他照片 还有那个保险箱里的其它东西
We give him the photos and everything else in that box
就可以留下剩下的 然后恢复清白自由之身了
and we get to keep the rest and we're free and clear.
这些人一般都不是什么好警察 玛蒂
These people are regular cozzers (bad cops), Martine.
我觉得比那更糟
They are above that.
他们比条子狠多了
They do things coppers can't.
他们肯定认为我们看过这照片了 我们已经没有利用价值了
They think we've seen these photos, we're expendable as dog shit.
你知道么?
You know what?
我明白我们现在的处境了 我不知道
I've seen our shots and I don't know...
如果不想坐以待毙 我们就要反击
we're either dog shit or about to beat dog shit.
我得走了
I'm out of here.
我可不打算在这里 等着条子来抓
I'm not waiting for a load of spooks and coppers to come cracking my head.
我要跟班巴一样尽快离开这
I'm splitting like Guy and Bambas.
我们一起行动比较好 戴夫
It would be better if we stuck together, Dave.
为什么 说说看? 难道是我们互相之间已经建立了某种信任?
And why, tell me?, 'cause we've been so truthful with each other so far?
戴夫 别这样 我得回家了 加文 去看我妈妈
- Dave, come on... - No, I'm going home, Kev. See my mom.
然后远走高飞 离你们越远越好
And then I'm going far away, as far as I can get away from you.
我们最好也离开这 万一班巴他们被逮住了
We'd better get out of here, too. In case Guy and Bambas get picked up.
我们分一下这些
Let's split the lot of this.
恐怕还有人不会放过我们
There may be someone else in this shit to cause us some more grief.
来一张 伙计 给
- One of those, mate. - Here you go.
不用找了 谢谢
- Keep the change. - Thanks.
[银行遭劫!]
[Find the Bank Raid!]
有人监听到我们的对话了 真该死!
- They overheard our radio chat. - Fuckin' hell...
"警察昨晚发现一家银行被劫30万"
"Police last night were trying to home in on a ?00.000 bank raid."
他们还不知道具体是哪家银行
They still don't know what bank it was.
30万? 我觉得不止这么点...
- 300 grand? - It's a bit more than that...
差不多有三百万
More like 3 million.
喂? Martine Love
- Hello? - Martine Love.
感谢上帝 快告诉我们点消息
Thank God. Put us through and then run a trace.
是我
It's me.
发生了什么? 你到底在哪?
What happened? Where the hell are you?
伦敦
London.
这我当然知道 我的意思是 在伦敦哪?
I know, of course. I mean, where?
我知道你什么意思
I know what you mean.
玛蒂 我们得见一面
Martine, we have to meet.
我没意见 不如你来我这吧?
I agree. Why don't you come over to my place?
我会给你准备鸡尾酒
I'll make you a cocktail,
然后我们就像以前一样 亲热一番
and we'll have a roll in the hay for old times' sake.
哦 很好 你在那 是吧?
Oh, right. You would have been there, haven't you?
你的人很可能已经在追查我了
Probably have your men keeping lookout for me now.
你现在没资格说这些 玛蒂
You're not in a position to play games, Martine.
别威胁我 提姆
No threats please, Tim.
为什么你之前没告诉我 帮你会是这种结果?
Why didn't you tell me what it was I was set up to get you?
这是为了你好
For your own good.
我很担心你的安危 玛蒂
I care about your safety, Martine.
是么
Right.
我以为我给了你想要的 然后我们就可以各走各的路了
I suppose I give you what you want and we go our separate ways.
我是这么说的
That's what I promised.
好吧 今天托特纳街2号
Ok, today. Tottenham Court Road 2.
北岛 北界月台 10:30整
Northern isle, northbound platform. 10:30 sharp.
托特纳街 10:30 没问题
Tottenham Court Road, 10:30. Good.
"电台无意收听到犯罪计划 全伦敦金库例行检查"
"London vaults checked after radio HAM tunes in to a crime."
上帝  真够失败的!
Christ, what a fiasco!
现在他们知道是哪家银行了
And now the particular bank has been identified,
到时候就会消息满天飞
the story will be all over the news.
现在已经是这样了
We've heard it already is.
如果我们不尽快搞定这个案子
If we don't get onto the case quickly
警察就会抓住那些抢劫犯了
the police will have nabbed these robbers,
到时候那些照片就会公之于众
and God knows what will happen to our photographs.
菲利普 去银行
Philip, get over to the bank.
去控制一下事态的发展
Take control of the situation.
绅士们 我刚刚跟Martine Love通了话
Gentlemen. I've just had a conversation with one Martine Love.
她在哪?
Where is she?
电话显示是在米勒广场 的一个公用电话亭
Call was traced to a public phone box on Miller's Court.
好消息是 她打算跟我见面
Good news is, she's arranged a meet.
的确是个好消息
That is good news.
我一个人去比较好 很好
- I'll be better off going alone. - Yeah.
提姆同意见面
Tim has agreed to meet.
到处都是关于抢劫的消息 他们找到那家银行了
It's all over the news. They found the location of the bank.
那又怎样?
So what?
不用找了
Keep the change.
不好意思 女士 你不能进去
I'm sorry, ma'am, you can't go in.
这里发生了一起劫案
There's been a robbery.
我们当然知道 不然我们干嘛来这
We know there's been a robbery, that's why we're all here.
这里的每个员工 每一个 去他那做笔录
Everybody that works here. I need everybody. Speak to him.
杰拉德?
Gerald?
你在管这个案子?
You work in robbery now then?
你很久没管过这种案子了
You're a long way off your patch.
我现在在地区犯罪小组
Regional crime squad now.
我只是过来看看情况如何
Just went by to see what all the fuss is about.
意外监听到劫案 很不错么
Pretty cheeky, that radio bit.
那些劫犯用对讲机联络的时候 肯定没想到已经被你发现了
These walkie-talkie robbers certainly caught your lot on the hop.
这让我们看起来很没用
Makes us all look stupid.
嗯 这个...
Yeah, well...
你跟城里的混混关系不错啊
You're pretty chummy with all the villains around town.
有没有想到是谁干的?
You got any idea who could have done this?
不可能是我的线人干的
None of my informers.
我们在这等了有一阵了
We have been waiting here quite some time,
而到现在为止你的人没能提供任何消息
and so far you people have told us absolutely nothing.
如果不介意的话 去列个失窃物品的清单
If you would like to give us an itemized list
我们到时候好确认
of the content of your boxes, we may be able to ascertain...
你疯了么?
- Are you mad? - ...what's missing.
你到底知不知道保险箱是用来干吗的
The whole point in having a safe deposit box
就是为了像你这样的人不知道里面有什么!
is so that people like you don't know what's in it!
我想跟罗伊.该文谈谈
I want to speak to a Roy Given.
我就是
Yeah, that's me.
这起抢劫案涉及到国家机密
This robbery is now a matter of national security.
我希望所有人都出去
I want everybody out.
现在是警方的例行调查
This is a police investigation.
我不想跟你废话 让你的上司来
Not anymore. Call your superiors.
他他妈的以为他是谁啊?
Who the bloody hell does he think he is?
特工 MI-5或6 我老是分不清
Spooks (agents). MI-5 or 6, I can never tell the difference.
他们看上去都差不多
They all got the same tailor
而且都是从一样的学校毕业
and they all went to the same bloody school.
我们去弄几个他们用对讲机
Let's get some copies of the...
对话内容的备份磁带
walkie-talkie tapes out to the news boys.
也许有人可以帮忙找到嫌犯
Maybe the public can help identify the villains.
告诉我 哪些保险箱被洗劫了?
So tell me... Which of the boxes were ransacked?
很多 大概四分之一
The lot. 100s through to 400s.
哦 我们有麻烦了 杰里 你和我
Oh, we're in a crapper, Jerry. Both of us.
我们? 为什么把我也卷进去了?
Both? Now, why is it my problem?
我们的账一直都做得很漂亮
Accounts have to be balanced records kept.
我一般不把它带在身边 所以?
And I wouldn't likely keep the books around here, now would I?
接着说 卢 具体点
Spell it out, Lew. Be more specific.
我有一个备份的账本
I have a ledger,
上面有每项支出的记录
a record of every payment
甚至包括每次给你们的好处也写在上面
I've ever made to you and your colleagues.
我把它放在保险箱里了
It was in my safety deposit box,
我以为那再安全不过了
and I think we can safely assume...
而它现在却落到那些劫匪的手里
it's now in the possession of the robbers.
上帝
Jesus wept.
我想你应该会同意
And I think you'll agree
在你的同事们逮到他们之前就抓住他们
we have to find those villains before your honest colleagues do.
真他妈该死
For fuck's sake.
谁?
Who is this?
卢.伍格
Lew Vogel.
等会 起来
Hold on. Get up.
快点 醒醒
Come on, wake up.
你想要干嘛 卢?
What do you want, Lew?
我恐怕要告诉你个坏消息 迈克
I'm afraid I've got some potentially bad news for you, Michael.
你存东西的那家贝克街的银行被抢了
Your safety deposit box at the Baker Street bank...
你的是保险箱是几号?
what's its number?
为什么这么问?
Why do you ask?
好吧 因为有人洗劫了银行金库
Well, because some thieves broke into the bank vault and robbed it.
如果你的保险箱在被劫之列
So if your box is in the 100 to 400 numbers,
恐怕你和你的兄弟们都会没命
I'm afraid all your stuff will be gone.
很可能连我也会没命
Mine too, unhappily.
什么? 伦敦怎么可能会发生这种事?
What? How can this happen in London?
好吧 但它确实发生了
Well, I promise you it has happened.
我答应你这些劫匪一旦被发现就会被干掉
I promise you these thieves will be found and dealt with.
你可以相信我 我会跟你保持联系
You can rely on it. I'll keep you informed.
谢谢
Thank you.
你最好保证没人会接近我或是跟踪我 不然玛蒂就会带着你的东西
No-one touches me, follows me or Martine takes your stuff...
远走高飞 听清楚了?
right to Fleet Street, understood?
你要的是118号保险箱 提姆
You want box 118, Tim.
你还不知道你现在的处境有多危险 对吧?
You have no idea of the danger you and your chums are in, do you?
是么? 能有多危险?
Is that right? And what would that be?
你已经打开了潘多拉的魔盒 你个白痴 这就是原因
You've opened Pandora's box, you dumb prick, that's why.
我知道谁处境比较危险
I know what's at stake.
而且我也知道我们有足够的时间
And I know how expendable we are.
计划有变
Some change in the deal.
哦 这可不行? 没错
- Oh, is that right? - Yeah...
我可以给你那些肮脏的照片 作为交换
You'll get all your nasty pictures, but here's the twist:
我们需要一些保障 新的护照以及出境通行证
We'll get indemnity, fresh passports, safe passage out of the country.
所有人都要
For the whole team.
还要有一份官方文件
And an officially signed document
保证我们不会被起诉 或是追捕
guaranteeing we won't be prosecuted and we won't be pursued.
你在开玩笑么?
You can't be serious?
我很认真 希望你也认真点
You can bet your bollocks I'm serious.
我希望这些都由权威机构
I want it signed and delivered by a public figure
签署和发放
of substantial authority.
让总理来签怎么样?
How about the Prime Minister?
嗯 他会签的 如果你对他的权利造成了威胁的话
Yeah, he'll do, if you can drag him off his yacht.
你打乱了我们的计划 提姆...
You mess with us, Tim...
我们可以把这些淫秽的照片发给媒体
We can drip-feed pictures like this to the press.
我们有一大摞呢
We've got a stack of 'em.
哦 是么?
Oh, do you?
四点之前给我们答复
You've got until 4pm to confirm that we have a deal.
我们会跟你保持联络
We'll be in touch.
一部分照片
Some photographs.
干得好 提姆!
Well done, Tim!
就这些?
Do you have any more?
显然 那个保险箱里还有很多这样的照片
Apparently there is a whole rose gallery stored in one of those boxes.
如果德拉斯亲王坚持这样奇怪的私生活方式
If Lord Drysdale is up to his usual hanky-panky (strange sex life),
恐怕那就是他自己的问题了
that's his problem.
我们的任务是把 迈克.X 的这些照片都给毁了
This operation is about recovering the photos from Michael X.
现在去让国会通过"D公告"
Might it not be prudent to get the committee
(国家机密安全防御公告)
to consider issuing a "D notice"?
是不是有点操之过急?
(defence notice to protect national secrets)
为了保护大家的利益
To protect everyone potentially
这真是个棘手的案子
embarrassed by this criminal activity.
我们正在查的这个
...Which we instigated.
很好 的确很不错
Very nice. Very nice indeed.
我出来的时候 看到有几个家伙在那照相
When I came out there were a couple of lads taking some photos.
就是他们
Buddies of him.
他就在银行外面 在银行被劫的几天之前
He was standing right outside the bank just a few days before it was robbed.
我那时就觉得他有点贼眉鼠眼
I thought at the time he looked a bit shifty.
天哪  这不会是真的吧?
Christ, is that thing real?
我想起来了
I've got it.
他叫戴夫.史令
Dave Shilling. That's his name.
好好照顾自己 妈妈
Tada (take care), mom.
你也是 儿子
Look after yourself, son.
快 快点进去 小心生病
Go, get yourself inside. You'll catch your death.
戴夫.史令? 是?
- Dave Shilling? - Yeah?
我们可以谈谈么
I wonder if we could have a word.
谈什么? 关于一家银行
- About what? - About a bank.
我想告诉你些事 史令先生
I want to tell you something, Mr. Shilling,
这样会节省不少时间
because it will save time.
你看
You see,
我对生活很悲观
I have a very jaundiced (bitter) view of life.
我所看到的大部分是 贪污 腐败和勾心斗角
From what I see, most of it is corrupt, venal and vile.
我之所以告诉你这些是为了
And I am just saying this so that you know
让你清楚最好不要抱侥幸心理
that I don't have a better nature to appeal to,
或者奢望我们会可怜你 我想 你应该明白这些 对吧?
or a compassionate streak. I mean, you do understand, don't you?
我想是的  伍格先生
I think so, Mr. Vogel.
很好
Good.
我有肾结石
I have a kidney stone,
疼起来的时候止痛药根本就没用
that does not seem to be able to pass without painkillers.
可以分我一点么
I could use a couple of those myself.
你偷了我的东西
You stole from me
也偷了我朋友的东西
and from friends of mine.
我的东西在哪? 我不知道
- Where is my stuff? - I don't know.
听着 我不知道什么银行劫案 真的
Look, I don't know anything about any bank robbery. Honest.
你的演技还是丝毫没有长进 史令先生
You're still an unconvincing actor, Mr. Shilling.
我很想告诉你这一点也不疼
I would love to say this is not going to hurt,
事实是它会很疼的
but it is.
你们要干吗?
What are you going to do?
不! 不
Please, no! No.
求你了 住手
Stop. Please.
不
No.
好吧 他们在这 你打算怎么办?
- Well, they were here. - What are you gonna do?
为什么门是开着的?
Why is the door open?
你们是谁?
Who are you?
这话该我问你
I could ask the same thing.
你们最好离开这 嗯?
You better run along, eh?
transcript by r o g a r d
去喝个茶或者干点别的什么
Get yourselves a cup of tea or something.
我们来找特里.莱泽
We are looking for Terry Leather.
Terry说他这周不会回来
Terry said he would not be coming in this week.
他本来应该打电话来的
He is supposed to call in.
那么你就是艾迪了 对吧 ? 嗯 是的
- So you would be Eddie, right? - Uh, yeah?
好 你跟我们一起走
Well, you're coming with me!
你们干什么? 放了他!
What are you doing? Leave him alone!
你们要把艾迪怎么样?
What are you going to do with my Eddie?
放轻松 放了他!
- Just relax. - Leave her alone!
我们想跟他聊一聊一桩银行劫案
We want to talk to him about a bank robbery.
别碰她!
Don't you touch her!
如果你还想见到艾迪 或是他的朋友戴夫
If you want to see your Eddie or his mate Dave again,
就让特里.莱泽打这个电话
make sure Terry Leather calls that number.
"对讲机"劫匪 将银行洗劫一空
Walkie-talkie gang takes it all.
号外号外
Read all about it.
"对讲机"劫匪 将银行洗劫一空
Walkie-talkie gang takes it all...
那是个不错的消息 完毕 我们可以歇一口气了
- That's great news. Over. - We're taking a break.
我们得好好睡上一觉
We need to get some sleep.
闭上眼好好休息下 我想把这该死的味道给洗了 完毕
Getting a shut-eye. I want the fumes cleared out. Over.
你运气比我好 我的眼睛像...
Lucky you. My eyes are like...
妈妈? 爸爸在广播里说话呢
Mommy? Daddy is on the radio.
亲爱的 别傻了
Don't be so silly, darling.
就是他!
He is!
是他么?
Is he?
我想洗个热水澡然后来上一杯茶 完毕
I want a warm bath and a cup of tea. Over.
你很快就可以喝上茶了 就像你平常那样 完毕
You'll get your cup of tea. Just your odd time. Over.
看? 就是爸爸
See? It is daddy.
警方已经公布了劳埃银行劫案中
Authorities have released this recording of the walkie-talkie
"对讲机"劫匪的部分通信和对话内容
communications between the robbers of Lloyds Bank in Marylebone
希望公众有人能通过声音
in the hopes that their voices
确定他们的身份
may be identified by members of the public...
喂?
Hello?
温迪?
Wendy?
我们在广播里听到你的声音了 特里 你知道么 你出名了?
We heard you on the radio, Terry. You are famous, you know?
你抢了那家银行 对不对? 新闻里说的那个
You robbed that bank, didn't you? The one on the news.
哦 上帝 你可能因为这个在牢里待上好几年 特里
Oh God, you could go to jail for years for something like that, Terry.
我可受不了这个
I couldn't stand it.
没有人会去坐牢
No one is going to jail.
我全都搞定了
I've got everyone under control.
老实呆着 别让孩子出去
Just stay put. Keep the kids inside.
我爱你 温迪
I love you, Wendy.
我得挂了
I gotta go.
小心点 特里
You be careful, Terry.
妈妈 怎么了?
What's the matter, mom?
没事 亲爱的
Nothing, darling.
特里 他们抓走了艾迪 哦 天哪 谁抓走了他?
- Terry, they took Eddie. - Oh God. Who?
他们没穿制服 我不知道 他们很可能是警察
They didn't have fleece (uniform) on. I don't know, they could have been cops.
他们留了个电话给你
They left a phone number for you.
他们说 如果你还想再见到 戴夫和艾迪
They said, if I want to see Dave or Eddie again,
最好跟他们联系
then you'll have to call.
听我说 我保证把他们带回来
Listen to me, I swear to you we'll get them back.
别担心 亲爱的
Don't you worry, darling.
你有笔么?
Have you got a pen?
有
Yeah.
0-1-9-4-6 别挂 再说一次
- 0-1-9-4-6. - Hold on, say it again.
0-1-9-4-6. 好
0-1-9-4-6. - Yeah.
迈克? 这是卢.伍格 没错
Michael? It's Lew Vogel. Yes.
很好 我们已经确定一名犯人了
Well, we've identified the villains.
信不信由你 他们只是跑龙套的
Believe it or not, they're amateurs. Part-timers.
是一个叫Martine Love的女人 让他们这么干的
They were put up to the job by a woman named Martine Love.
认识她么? 从没听过这个人
- Ring a bell? - Never heard of her.
好吧 我们已经让人去她的公寓了
Well, we paid a visit to her flat,
只是军情五处的人已经在那了
and some chaps from MI-5 were already there.
把我的人给赶走了
Pulled rank on my tame copper.
你觉得是什么让这些人
Why do you suppose these people would be interested
对一起小小的银行劫案如此感兴趣呢 迈克?
in the robbery of a minor neighbourhood bank, Michael?
我不知道 我想你知道
- I don't know. - I think you do.
我猜你的保险箱是118号?
And I'm guessing that your box is number 118?
而且我觉得那些劫匪恐怕 就是冲着那些照片去的
I think what these robbers were really after were photographs.
关系到一位公主的照片
Photographs of a certain Royal Princess.
你是怎么知道的?
How do you know that?
至于这个 是这些劫匪告诉我的
Because on this point, I believe my captive.
没人可以受得起我们的拷问
No man could withstand the pain we inflicted on him.
所以别把我当傻瓜 迈克!
So don't take me for a fool, Michael!
都是因为你把你敲诈的证据
You've instigated this calamity
存到了这家银行
by storing your blackmail materials in this bank.
那银行是你推荐的
Which you recommended.
我才不要被这些昏君管制
I will not be lectured by the porn king of Soho.
拿回我的照片
Get my pictures back,
否则你就会看到伦敦街上出现
or you will never see a black man on the streets of London
一个无论如何都要干掉你的黑人!
without wondering if he's been sent to kill you!
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
哦 好啊 迈克 哈蒂姆在找他书的一份复印稿
Oh, hello Michael. Hakim was looking for a copy of his book.
我知道你在找什么
I know what you've been looking for.
你找不到的
You won't find it.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
哈蒂姆 我找到你的稿子了
Hakim, I found your book.
你不会理解的
You don't understand.
我和我朋友的那些保险箱
My box and those of my friends
很可能被抢了
may have been rifled.
你显然可以做点什么
Surely you can pull some strings.
你可是部长 看在上帝的份上!
You're a minister in the government, for God's sake!
索尼娅我觉得 在这件事上我可能帮不了你
Sonia, I really don't think I am able to help here.
可能你还不是很清楚
Perhaps you don't fully comprehend.
我有你的照片 你寻欢作乐的照片
I have photographs, compromising photographs,
甚至还有你的录像
live filmed of you,
迈尔斯.厄科特 还有其他的常客的
Miles Urquhart, all my regulars,
都在这个保险箱里
in this safe deposit box.
不过你们倒是可以借机互相认识一下
You all know each other if that's any consolation.
你居然偷偷给我拍了照片?
You've got photographs of me?
你这个阴险的婊子!
You conniving cunt! (conspiring)
是你太天真了
You be a big boy.
现在是时候跟你那些 白厅的朋友好好谈谈了
Now is the time to talk to your White Hall chums,
你不这么觉得么?
don't you think?
就是他 就是他没错
That's him. Sure that's him.
亚瑟.斯纳 十足的骗子加犯罪分子
Guy Arthur Singer, con man and petty criminal.
坐过几年的牢
Did a stretch in the "Scrubs" (prison) a few years back.
我觉得他应该是个手淫者 听他讲话的口气就像
I thought he was a wanker. Spoke with some poncey accent.
谢谢你 先生 非常感谢
Thank you, sir, very much.
喂? 你是谁?
- Hello? - Who am I talking to?
特里,莱泽 加文.斯文 Martine Love 艾迪.博尔顿
Terry Leather, Kevin Swain, Martine Love, Eddie Burton.
嗯 史令先生 很识趣的把你们都供了出来
Yeah, Mr. Shilling was kind enough to speak with me about this.
让戴夫听电话
You put Dave on the phone.
我会让他听的 但是
Now, I would, but...
他现在好像有点不舒服
he seems a bit indisposed at the moment.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
只不过是你们偷的东西的一小部分
Just a couple of things from what you've stolen.
一本深红色封面的账本
A ledger with a dark red cover.
和一些照片
And some photos
我相信军情五处对它们很感兴趣
that I'm sure the MI-5 is interested in.
"皇室文件"
The "Royal portfolio".
我们只有钱和首饰
All we got is money and jewels.
那你最好再仔细找找
Then I suggest you look again.
跟你朋友说吧
Speak to your friends.
喂 是谁? 艾迪 我是特里
- Hello, who is this? - Eddie, it's Terry.
特里...
Terry...
特里 该死
Terry, fucking hell.
戴夫把什么都招了
Dave is all messed up,
他们也打算这么对付我 你得来救我
and they're going to do the same to me, you got to help.
听我说 艾迪
Listen to me, Eddie.
我没有他想要的东西
I don't have what he wants.
没有? 不 你有的 你该有的
No? No, you've got to have what they want, you've got to.
不管怎么说你得帮我
You've got to help.
艾迪 我该怎么帮? 你告诉他 你没有他们要的东西!
Eddie, what am I supposed to do? You tell him, we don't have it!
别 特里 特里你最好... 艾迪
- No, Terry. Terry, you gotta-- - Eddie,
告诉他我没有他要的该死的账本!
Tell him I don't have his fucking ledger!
你现在告诉那个混蛋!
You tell that cunt now!
他说他没有...
He doesn't have it...
很好
Right.
等等...
Wait...
不! 不!
No! No!
不! 他们杀了戴夫!
No! They shot Dave!
艾迪? 戴夫死了
- Eddie? - Dave is dead.
艾迪! 他们开枪杀了他 特里...
- Eddie! - They shot him, Terry...
我给你一个小时去找我要的东西
I'll give you one hour to find what I want,
不然我就杀了他 滴答...
or I'll kill this man. Tick...
就是这个
This is it.
卢.伍格
Lew Vogel.
就是这个混蛋
That's what this bastard is.
"伦敦西区警察及高官行贿支出"
"Payments made to Soho and West End division officers"
这个星期的支出 这里50镑 那里20镑
There are weekly payouts. 50 quid here, 20 there.
可能伦敦的每一个烂警察都在这本子上
Probably every bad copper in London.
事情不该是这么发展的
Nothing like this was supposed to happen.
没人该受伤
No one was supposed to get hurt.
不是你的错 是么?
It's not your fault, right?
我们还得给自己想想出路 还有艾迪
We still got our own exit to think about, and Eddie.
如果我们把照片给了伍格 就违反了跟提姆的协议
If we give the photos to Vogel, all bets are off with Tim.
如果我们把它给了提姆 艾迪就性命不保
If we deliver it to Tim, it's Eddie's neck
而且伍格也会一直追杀我们
and Vogel is still after us.
两条路都走不通
Either way we are fucked.
迈尔斯 我们惹上麻烦了
Miles, we've got a problem,
大麻烦
a serious problem.
关于索尼娅.波恩 存在银行保险箱的一些东西
Something Sonia Bern kept in the bank
就是上周被抢了的那家银行
that was robbed over the weekend.
她说她的保险箱
She is concerned that her safe deposit box
很可能就在被劫之列
may have been plundered.
我觉得她的担心不无道理
I'm afraid her fears are well justified.
哦 上帝
Oh my God.
我一直觉得索尼娅是个很有城府的女人
I really thought Sonia was a woman of more discreet character.
所以... 恶魔出动了
So... The genie is out of the bottle then.
我们两个都被盯上了 嗯? 差不多
- For both of us, ey? - Not quite yet.
我的直觉告诉我这些劫匪
My operatives tell me that the thieves
正在利用这些照片作为砝码
are using the photographs as a bargaining chip.
那就给他们想要的 我们正是这样做的
- Then give them what they want. - Already in motion.
然后让国会通过"D公告"
And the committee having done the works
来搞定这件事
to issue a "D-notice" on the whole business.
让媒体都闭嘴 给他们一点好处
To muffle (silence) the press. Put a lid on it.
真是遗憾 不是么?
Big pity, wouldn't it?
如果你的朋友因为一些照片而抛弃了你
Well, if your mates abandoned you over a few photographs.
喂
Hello.
听我说 不管你是叫"伍格"还是他妈的什么
You listen to me, Mr."Vogel" or whatever your fucking name is.
你直接杀了他好了 我们什么都不会给你的
You go ahead and kill him, we don't give a shit.
我们找到我们的战利品了
We got our loot.
你的账本还有那些照片
Your ledgers and your photos,
你永远都不会拿到它们
you can pick them up from Scotland Yard.
我们现在就把他们公之于众
We're sending them over.
别那样
Don't do that.
好吧 既然你想要拿回你的账本
Well, if you want your book of payoffs back,
明天上午11点一个人来 帕丁顿站一号月台
be at Paddington Station in person tomorrow 11 am, platform 1.
军官雕塑旁边的那个书报摊
There's a newsstand near the statue of the soldier.
带上艾迪 老狐狸
Have Eddie with you, hale and hearty.
这是你唯一的机会伍格
This is your one and only chance, Vogel.
别搞砸了
Don't blow it.
别去开门! 卡瑟琳!
Don't answer it! Catherine!
爸爸! 你好么
- Daddy! - How are you?
来这
Come here.
过来 看 我给你带了礼物
Here. Look, I got you a present.
有没有乖乖听妈妈的话啊? 当然
- You been good for mommy? - Yeah.
我得跟妈妈谈点事
I need to talk to mommy about something,
让我们单独待会 行么?
so give us a minute, okay?
进去吧 好孩子
- Go on. - Good girls.
你现在愿意告诉我发生了什么了么?
So.. you want to tell me what's been going on?
有人拷问了戴夫 他怎么样了
- Some blokes were tough at Dave. - How bad?
他已经死了
He's dead.
哦 上帝 特里
Oh my God Almighty, Terry.
你对我们做了什么?
What have you done to us?
温迪 我保证 我会搞定的
Wendy, I promise, I'm gonna work this out.
一旦我脱身 我们就离开英国
And when I do, we're going to leave England.
这一切都会过去的
and it's all going to change for us.
不过一旦有什么不对 用这个
But if anything goes wrong, use this.
这里有些现金 英镑 法郎还有美元
There is plenty of cash. Pounds, francs, dollars.
你得离开这里
You're going to leave the country,
带着孩子们开始新的生活
start a new life for you and the girls.
你可以做到的 温迪  答应我
You can do this if you have to, Wendy. Promise me.
这是抢来的 对吧?
Is that from the robbery, is it?
没错 我的那份
My share, yeah.
报纸上说有个女人也参与了抢劫
The papers said there was a woman in the vault.
玛蒂 所以她也跟这个有关?
Martine, so was she involved?
没错 一开始就是她让我们这么干的
Yeah. She brought us the job in the first place.
哦 所以你跟她上床了 特里?
Oh, and did you sleep with her, Terry?
从那天起我就看出来了 她看上去就是这种人
I did know that from day one. It was the way she looked.
我们第一次见面的时候我就 跟我的朋友奥迪说
The first day we met I said to my friend Audrey, I said:
"我会嫁给这个男人然后给他生孩子"
"I am gonna marry him. And I am gonna have his kids."
我一直这么相信你 不管别人怎么说我一直都相信你!
And I have stood by you and I will stand by you no matter what!
你这个混蛋!!
You bastard!!
该死...
Fuck...
你可以尽管骂我
You can firm me over. (yell at me)
是我活该
I deserve it.
我没让你过上幸福生活反而让你遭罪
I brought you more grief than happiness,
但是我爱你还有孩子们
but I love you. And the kids.
我之所以这么干是想赌一次 为了让我们过上好日子
So the reason I did this was to get us out of this life once and for all.
妈妈 开门!
Mommy, open the door.
妈妈 妈妈!
Mommy, mommy!
我们还有这么长的日子 回房间去玩!
- We have the rest of our lives, - Go play in your room!
如果你还相信我
...if you'll still have me.
她照的真不错 嗯 提姆?
She takes a good picture, eh, Tim?
蒙巴顿亲王 对你处理这个关乎皇室声誉的事件
Lord Mountbatten has graciously agreed to represent
的表现非常满意
the interest of the crown in this matter.
他够不够高层? 蒙巴顿亲王
- Is he high enough up the tree? - Lord Mountbatten.
我一直都想见见那个淫棍
I always wanted to meet that bugger.
嗯 我不是很确定他 是否乐意见你
Yes. I am not sure he will be very pleased to meet you, too.
他必须得在十一点站在帕丁顿站的大钟下面 不然协议就作废
He has to be under the main clock Paddington Station, 11 am, or no deal.
11点 知道了
11 am, on the knock,
还有你们的新护照和文件
and with your new passports and documents.
他只要看到照片就会马上给你们的
He's gonna hand them over as soon as he sees the photos.
还有个问题
There's another problem.
这起抢劫惊动了一些本地的家伙
This robbery's pissed off some local villains.
枪打出头鸟 嗯?
The guts come with the glory, eh?
我们中有人被杀了
One of our mates has been killed.
混混们会这么干也没什么好奇怪的
That's hardly surprising considering the roster of reprobates
是在那家银行存放保险箱的顾客
that are the banks' deposit box customers.
听着 特里 我们的协议是...
Listen, Terry. Our committment is for...
交出皇室的照片 仅此而已
the recovery of the royal...portraits only.
至于这些混混你最好自己搞定
The proceeds and the piss-offs are both yours to deal with.
上午11点 帕丁顿站
11 am, Paddington Station.
盖儿
Gale.
迈克在花园等着见你
Michael wants to see you in the garden.
为什么? 我不知道
- What for? - I don't know.
盖儿 过来 进来看看这个
Gale, come. Come and look at this.
快来
Come.
我想给你看点东西 这是干嘛?
- I want to show you something. - What's this for?
这是给你挖的
It's for you.
我做了什么你们要这么对我? 我到底做了什么?
What have I done to deserve this? What have I done?
你这个间谍 被派到我这来窃取信息的
You're a spy, sent to steal from me.
没有人可以从迈克.X这偷到东西 没人可以!
And nobody steals from Michael X. No-one!
看有没有提到管这个案子的警官
See if it mentions the copper in charge.
找到了
Here it is.
"这起案件由探长负责
"Heading the case is Detective Sergeant
"还有玛丽波恩警署的罗伊.该文 "
"Roy Given of Marylebone Lane police station."
罗伊.该文?
Roy Given?
这里没有罗伊.该文
No Roy Given menioned.
希望这能意味着他是个好警察
Let's hope that means he's straight.
最好他对警察里出了哪些败类感兴趣
And that he'd be interested in the names of some bent coppers.
嗯 希望如此
Yeah, a bit of a long shot.
该死
Fuck it...
那张上面没消息么? 没有
- Nothing in that one? - No.
甚至连只言片语都没有 就好像我们没干过这事?
Well, we don't rate a mention. Strike you as strange?
这才是真正让人害怕的
It's kind of scary actually.
如果这个消息可以消失 我们也可能会消息
If that news could disappear, so could we.
下一站 艾其威尔路
Next stop: Edgware Road.
好吧
Well...
我们在这分手吧
Here's to us.
再见 伙计
See you, mate.
好好照顾自己 保重
Look after yourself. Take care.
好运 加文
Good luck, Kev.
你现在打算去哪? 如果一切照计划进行的话?
So where are you headed? If everything goes to plan?
如果你跟我一起我就告诉你
I'll tell you, if you're coming with me.
早上好 我找罗伊.该文先生
Good morning. I'm looking for a mister Roy Given.
我有很重要的事
It's very important.
罗伊.该文? 我就是
- Roy Given? - Yeah.
请问有什么重要的事?
Can I ask what it's concerning?
哦 我更想跟他当面说
No, I prefer to tell him myself.
听着 我要说的是 如果你对账本上
Look, all I'm saying is, if you're interested
剩下的东西有兴趣的话
in the rest of this book of payoffs,
它的主人现在就在帕丁顿站
the author's gonna be at Paddington Station
11点 一号月台
11 am, platform one.
你是怎么弄到这个的?
And how exactly did this come into your possession?
下一站  帕丁顿站 乘客们请在此转乘贝克鲁线
Next stop: Paddington Station. Change here for the Bakerloo line.
希望他也常常迟到
Let's hope now he turns up fashionably late.
你的朋友提姆在那呢 祝你好运
- There's your friend, Tim. - Good luck.
真高兴看到你没事
It's good to see you in one piece.
你一直担心的都是自己的安危 提姆 你根本没担心过我
You were worried for your own arse, Tim, not for mine.
你是个混蛋 提姆
You're a prick, Tim.
你从一开始就利用了我 对吧?
You set this whole thing up from the start, didn't you?
别这样 你马上就会拥有财富 自由和清白
Come on, you get to be rich, free and clear.
这些不正是你想要的么?
Isn't that what you wanted?
你在车里待着 好
- You stay here with the car. - Right.
该死的肾结石 很快就可以结束了
Bloody kidney stone. It's gotta go out soon.
自从战争结束后我很久没这么兴奋过了
I haven't had this much excitement since the war.
我们已经迟到了 陛下
We're a little late, Mylord.
你的朋友在哪呢?
So where is your mate?
就在那 先生 在书报摊旁边的那个
There, sir, that one at the newsstand.
等等 我之前在那个女人的公寓见过这两个人
Wait. I've seen those two cowboys before at the girl's flat.
这是个陷阱 他们是军情五处 特里
- It's a trap, they're MI-5. - Terry.
特里
Terry.
蒙巴顿亲王? 嗯?
- Lord Mountbatten? - Yes?
你知道我们的协议 并且也同意给我们签署新护照
You know the arrangements and you agree to our new identities
以及法律免责书么?
and immunity from prosecution?
只要有我的签名 国会会承认其法律效力的
You have my word that the crown will honour this committment.
你要的文件和护照
Your documentation and guarantees
如果我是你 我会把他们放在一个很安全的地方
If I were you, I'd keep them in a very safe place.
嗯  希望不会是放在一个保险箱
Yeah, well, you bet it won't be a safe deposit box.
她一直都这么放浪不羁 谢谢
She is a scallywag (rogue). Thank you.
玛蒂
Martine.
这不都是为了我自己
It wasn't all business for me.
发生了什么 账本呢? 开门
- What happened, where's the book? - Just open the door.
不! 给我进去
- No! Get in there.
老实呆着 不然就干掉你!
Stay there, or you're dead meat!
你想去哪 老家伙 啊?
Where are you going, old man, eh?
不!
No!
这一下是为了戴夫 别
- This one's for Dave. - No...
你这个混蛋!
You fucker!
现在怎么不嚣张了 啊?
Not so fucking smug now, are you?
哦 你这个家伙!
Oi, you punk!
艾迪 快出来 就是他杀了戴夫
- Eddie, get out. - That's the one that killed Dave.
把你的手拿开!
Get your hands off me!
逮捕他们 他们是银行劫匪
Arrest them, they are bank robbers.
该死! 这家伙杀了我们的朋友!
- Fuck! - This bloke killed our friend!
靠 不不 听着
- Shit. - No, no, listen...
我们现在是不是真的完了  特里?
So, are we seriously arseholed now, Terry?
嗯 至少我们没有像戴夫一样连命都搭上了
Well, at least we're not dead like poor old Dave.
起来  你这个老混蛋
Get up, you filthy bastard.
你被捕了 带走他
You're under arrest. Take him away.
知道 你 过来
All right. Come on, you.
进车里去
Get in the car.
没事了 伙计们
It's all right, mate.
那该不会就是罗伊.该文吧?
I wonder if that's Roy Given?
哪个?
Who's he?
我还期望他会是个好警察
I was hoping he was a straight copper.
干得不错 罗伊
We've got a nice collar (catch) here, Roy.
知道么 就是这两个人参与了 贝克街银行的抢劫案
You know, these two are part of the Baker Street bank robbery gang.
把这个人抓起来 是 长官
- Place this man under arrest. - Yes, sir.
你在说什么? 是他们抢了那家银行
What are you talking about? They're part of the Baker Street Firm.
这我可不清楚
I don't know about that.
但是我很清楚你 你这个贪赃枉法的混蛋
But I know all about you, you corrupt bastard.
把他铐起来 墙那边那个也给拷上
Cuff him. The one over by the wall as well.
他们才是劫匪!
But they are the robbers!
这里没有劫匪
No robbers in here.
小心你的头
Watch your head.
现在
Now...
我相信你一定也觉得伍格先生账本上的 那些警察会让我们感到丢脸
I believe you've a certain Mr. Vogel's book of shame.
如果你放我走 我就帮你去找到那个账本
Well, if you let me out, I'll go get it for you.
那是我的
That belongs to me.
给你
Here's your book.
特里 我们觉得像你这么一个精明的人
Terry. We were thinking, a smart fella like you
为了以防万一应该会经常做点笔记
might have kept mementos of the event, just in case.
以防万一? 看来事情没有想象中的顺利?
Case what? Things didn't turn out so nicely?
只要他们可以活过今天
If they should ever see the light of day
别以为我们找不到你
don't think we can't find you.
出来 快点滚
Out. Go on, piss off.
你还没走?
Aren't you gone?
这到底是怎么回事? 我他妈的怎么知道 快点走
- How did that happen? - Fucked if I know, just keep walking.
迈克 迈克!
Michael, Michael!
怎么了? 你们想干吗?
What's going on? What do you want in my place?
你们到底要干吗?
What do you want?
我们现在要逮捕你 我犯了什么事?
- We are placing you under arrest. - What am I charged with?
密谋往英国走私毒品 这样可以了?
Conspiracy to import drugs into the United Kingdom, will that do?
给你一个将功赎罪的机会
But you could still help yourself.
告诉我们盖儿.本森在哪
There's a British national staying with you, a certain Gale Benson.
她刚在这 不过已经走了
She was here, but she's gone on.
很好 手放在后面!
- All right. - Get in the back!
在这 长官
Over here, sir.
把这房子烧了
Burn the house down.
别留下任何东西
I want nothing of this place left standing.
你们是戴夫的朋友么? 哦 是的
- Were you friends of Dave? - Oh yeah.
真的?
- Really?
我们在拍电影的时候认识的
We knew him in a professional capacity.
我们很喜欢他
He was one of our favourites.
回头见
See you later.
你还好吧? 嗯
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
结束后你要去哪 加文?
So where are you off to, Kevin?
你去哪我就去哪
Anywhere you want to go.
抱歉 我打算一直单身
Sorry, I'm doing a solo from now on.
嗯 好吧
Yeah, well.
不错的尝试
It was worth a try.
你有没有考虑过其他人?
Do you want another one?
嗯 有过 在街上碰到的
Yeah, go on. One for the road.
干杯
Tummy (cheers).
我真希望戴夫可以跟我们一起
I just wish Dave could have seen all this.
是啊 这一杯为了戴夫
Yeah... Here's to Dave.
为了戴夫
To Dave.
你想干嘛 玛蒂?
What do you want, Martine?
不好意思让你这么不高兴 温迪
I'm sorry I've caused you this upset, Wendy.
嗯 显然我们已经变的有钱了
Well, apparently we're rich.
我知道事情已经结束了 但是这车真的是我们的了么?
I know the business is finished, but are the cars really ours?
当然
Yeah.
都是你的
They are all yours.
你们该得的
Jessul has been paid off.
我不想骗你
I won't lie to you...
我本来想跟他远走高飞
I would have gone with him,
我本来想不顾你的感受的
and I would have shut you out of my mind,
但是他不这么想
but he didn't want to know.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你老婆在跟玛蒂聊天 我知道 加文
- Your wife is talking to Martine. - I know, Kev.
我知道
I know...
祝你好运
Good luck.
你一点都没变 特里
It was always you, Terry.
爸爸!
Daddy!
嘿!
Hey!
哦天哪  特里 这可是条大鱼
Oh my God, Terry, that's a big one.
可以好好吃上一顿了 对吧?
Lash a few chips on that, all right?
黑鱼... 妈妈 别!
- Black... - Don't, mom!
今晚有鱼吃了 嗯? 真听话
- Fish fingers tonight, aye? - What a pretty boy...
[劫案结束后不久伦敦的苏格兰警场]
[Soon after the robbery Scotland Yard underwent]
[展开了一项贪污官员的清理运动]
[a major purge of corrupt police officers]
[很多高官都因此被免职]
[A number of senior members of the government resigned]
[接着索尼娅.波恩的妓院也被查封]
[following revelations about the activities at Sonia Bern's brothel]
[迈克.X 1975年在特尼德被绞死]
[Michael X was hanged in 1975 in Trinidad]
[罪名是谋杀了盖儿.本森]
[for the murder of Gale Benson.]
[直到2054年一月之前他的那些照片]
[His file in the British National Archive remains classified]
[仍是皇室的机密文件]
[until the 1st of January 2054]
[皮条客伍格因为 对劫案知情不报判刑八年]
[Porn King Vogel was jailed for 8 years for crimes unrelated to the robbery]
[哈蒂姆.加摩尔1973年在波斯顿被谋杀]
[Hakim Jamal was murdered in Boston in 1973]
[杀害盖尔还有班巴的凶手 一直逍遥法外]
[The murders of Guy and Bambas were never solved]
[贝克街损失的财物据估计]
[The loot taken from the Baker Street Bank]
[约有400多万英镑]
[was thought to be in excess of 4 million pounds,]
[比火车劫案的数目要庞大的多]
[more than that of the Great Train Robbery]
[一百多名拥有保险箱的顾客拒绝]
[Over 100 safe deposit box holders refused...]
[认领他们在银行存放的物品]
[to identify their losses from the robbery]
[这部影片里很多人物的身份已经得到确认]
[The names of many of the people identified in this film]
[他们一直都在包庇犯罪]
[have been changed to protect the guilty]
Rogard的手稿 还有Lyliakar的帮助
transcript by rogard, with a little help from lyliakar
制作：jesseding
Please respect my hard work. Don't remove these credits. Thanks.